[MUSIC]
［音乐］
Stanford University.
斯坦福大学
Okay, well welcome to Stanford CS193p, Winter of 2015.
欢迎来到2015冬季学期，斯坦福大学CS193P课程。
This is lecture number five.
这次是第五讲。
And, today we're gonna finish up
这次我们要继续上次没讲完
what were talking about last time.
的内容。
And talk a little bit about Objective-C compatibility,
然后再说一点关于Objective-C兼容性的问题。
because, of course iOS was originally written in
因为iOS起初是用Objective-C 这种
an entirely different language.
完全不同于Swift的语言写的。
And so there's a little bit of
所以在旧世界和Swift的世界中间
bridging between the Swift world and the old world.
需要有一个桥接。
And we're gonna talk about an example of
然后我们会讲 Property List，这是适用
using AnyObject which is Property Lists.
AnyObject的又一个例子。
And I'm gonna do a kind of a brief demo even,
这里我会用一个简单的
showing you that.
demo来演示这个。
Then we're gonna move onto a completely new topic, which is views.
然后我们就要开始一个全新的课题，view
So, views on how we draw, and how we handle touch input.
是关于在我们的UI里，如何绘制view，
In our UI and so we're gonna go over that, and
如何响应触屏事件，先讲一些内容，然后
I'll be having a demo for that as well.
依然会有一个demo。
So, I'm gonna blast through these slides pretty quick.
幻灯片我可能会讲的比较快。
As usual, the demonstration is probably
总体来说，示例会比幻灯片更
a little more elucidating then some of the slides, cuz when
容易让你们理解，因为当你们真正看见如何做的
you see it in action, it's a lot easier to understand.
时候，知识会容易理解的多。
Okay.
So, Objective-C compatibility, so, virtually all the iOS API,
下面开始讲 Objective-C 兼容的问题， 基本上iOS全部的API都是
this API that was written over the last, however many years,
在之前许多年内用 Objective-C 写的。
in Objective-C, is available from Swift.
现在在Swift里也可以用。
And you can't even tell the difference, okay?
甚至你都看不出区别来。
It's just kind of, automatically made available.
就好像非常自然的就可以用一样。
And, when they designed Swift,
但是当他们设计Swift的时候，
they went to a lot of trouble to make sure that it would,
为了达到非常好的兼容性，他们遇到了
could be done in a very compatible way.
很多麻烦。
So, that all of the iOS API, would work,
所以现在的这些 API，在Swift里
just fine in Swift.
还算能用。
There's few special data types though, that they've gone
但是有一些特殊的数据类型，在交接两种语言的
to special care to bridge between the two languages,
时候需要特殊的注意。
and this makes using iOS API from Objective-C, much easier
这使得使用 Objective-C 调用 iOS API的时候，会比Swift
in Swift, and so, I'm gonna talk briefly about those.
容易很多，我下边会简要的说一下这个问题。
One is NSString.
其中一个就是 NSString 。
That is the old way that String were represented,
这是String以前的形式，
in iOS, and that is bridged interchangeably to
在iOS里， 它与Swift的String
Swift's String.
是可以互换使用的。
You can't really even tell the difference.
甚至可以当它们没有区别。
If you have a method that takes an NSString,
如果有一个方法接受 NSString 的参数，
you can pass a Swift String in there, and vice-versa.
你可以传一个Swift的String进去，反之亦然。
Okay, they're just automatically treated if
尽管他们两个是非常不同的东西，
they were the same thing,
它们还是被当成
even though they are quite different things.
完全一样的。
String in Swift is not even a class.
Swift里的String甚至都不是一个类，
Okay, its just a struct.
而仅仅是一个 struct 。
So, they've done some miraculous work to
苹果的人做了非常神奇的工作把
bridge these things.
它们桥接了起来。
NSArray, which is the old Array,
数组的老版本， NSArray，
is bridged to Array of AnyObject.
桥接到Swift 里就是 AnyObject 元素组成的数组。
Okay, so any time you see, an Array of AnyObject in
所以以后只要你们在iOS的API里看到
an iOS API, it's because it was an NSArray before, okay?
AnyObject 的数组，说明他们以前都是 NSArray 。
Then NSDictionary is an interesting one,
NSDictionary 是比较有趣的一个，
it's bridged to Dictionary where the keys have to be
在Swift里，它被桥接成键是 NSObject 的子类对象
subclasses of NSObject, and the values are AnyObject, okay?
而值是 AnyObject
Now, you might think, that's gonna be a problem, and
你们可能觉得这样会有问题，
I'll explain why that's not in a moment.
我一会儿会解释为什么目前这样做没问题。
And then of course, Int and
然后，Int， Float
Float, Double, Bool, they are all bridged to NSNumber.
Double， Bool，他们都是从 NSNumber 桥接过来的。
We talked briefly about NSNumber,
我们之前简单的讲过 NSNumber ，
we talked about the NSNumberFormatter and all that.
我们讲了 NSNumberFormatter 还有其他东西。
So, NSNumber was the old Objective-C object that
所以， NSNumber 是 Objective-C 里所有关于
just meant, any kind of numeric value.
数值的对象。
And, so anything that used to take an NSNumber, you can
所以在所有用到 NSNumber的地方，你传入一个
pass a Double, or Float or Int in there, and it'll just work.
Double，Float 或者 Int 都是没问题的。
Of course, coming back the other way isn't automatic,
当然反过来是不行的，
because it doesn't really know necessarily what you want.
因为那样系统就不知道你到底需要那种数字类型了。
But you can use the methods like doubleValue or
当然你可以用类似 doubleValue 或者
IntValue, like we use doubleValue, in the Calculator.
IntValue 的这样的方法， 比如我们在计算器里就用了 doubleValue。
And of course, Int and Float and Double are also bridged to
当然 Int Float 和 Double 都是和 C 语言
the C types int, float, and double.
里的int，float 和 double 桥接好的。
So, you have an API that takes an int, and hold a C int.
所以如果一个API里结构一个C语言的int参数，
It'll be bridged to take capital I Swift Int.
它也可以接受一个 Swift 里的 Int （I是大写的）。
So, this stuff, all just works completely automatically.
这个特性是完全自动生效的，
And you don't ever have to do anything.And it just works.
我们什么都不需要做。
However, if you wanna be explicit, about the type,
然后，如果你需要非常明确的类型，
you can cast, okay?
你可以做类型转换。
So, it is perfectly legal to cast a Swift String to
把 Swift 的String转换成 NSString 是完全合法的，
an NSString, and it will always work, so
不会有任何问题，
you don't need as?
并且不需要 as？。
Okay, it's all a hundred percent guaranteed cast.
这是完全安全的转换。
And then once you do that,
如果你这么做，
you have an NSString instead of a String, and so
你就把之前的String转换成了 NSString ，
you can send it messages that are in NSString.
你就可以给它发送 NSString 的消息了。
Although you wanna be careful with some of them,
你们也需要注意一些问题，
like length, is an NSString method,
比如length 是一个 NSString，
that doesn't exist on String.
在 String 里并不存在。
It doesn't exist on String for a reason.
它在 String 里不存在是有原因的，
Because, we talked about this before, you know,
我们曾经讲过，
the length of a Unicode String, can vary,
Unicode 字符串的长度是可变的，
compared to the number of glyphs you'll see on screen,
根据你在屏幕上看到符号的不同而不同，
and the new Swift String deals with that, and the old
新的 Swift 的 String 会处理此类字符串，但是 NSString 确实
NSString doesn't really deal with that properly.
没有很好的处理。
So, you gotta be careful, when you start calling NSString
所以当你要调用 NSString 方法的时候要特别小心，
methods that, you know,
there's not, you wanna look for a String equivalent, and
尽量用 String 代替，因为
use that if you can, because it's newer, and
String 是最新的，
it does thinks a little more accurately.
而且可以更精确。
But NSArray is the same thing, you can cast from an Array,
NSArray 也是一样的， 你可以从 Swift 的 Array
that you have in Swift, to an NSArray, and
转换到它，
then you can call them methods in NSArray.
然后你就可以调用 NSArray 的方法了。
Like componentsJoinedByString, which is kinda cool,
比如 componentsJoinedByString 就是一个很酷的方法，
it takes all the components in the Array,
它收集数组中的所有元素，
sends them description, takes those descriptions and
给它们一个描述，然后用传进来的字符串把
joins them by the String you pass as an argument.
它们连接起来。
This is the same as the join method in Swift's String.
这个跟Swift里String的join方法是一样的。
Okay, so, you can look at the documentation for
你们可以去查阅 String，NSString 和 NSArray
String and, NSString and NSArray, but
的官方文档，
pretty much all the things you can do there, or most
基本上所有的东西，或者说大多数的东西，
of them anyway, are available in the Swift versions.
都可以在Swift里用。
But again, if you're passing them back and
如果你在两个版本里转换，
forth, it's all automatic, so you'd say.
可以说都是自动的过程。
Now, you might get a little concerned about Dictionary,
好的，你们对 Dictionary 可能还有点疑问，
because Dictionary, the key has to be an NSObject.
因为字典的键必须是 NSObject。
And of course, we know that String, and Array, and
当然我们知道，String，Array 和 Dictionary 在 Swift
Dictionary in Swift, are not even objects, okay?
里都不是对象。
They're not AnyObject, or
它们既不是 AnyObject ，
they're, and they're not an NSObject for sure.
当然更不是 NSObject 。
But you can still pass them anywhere you wanna pass in
但是我们依然可以在需要传 AnyObject 类型 或者 NSObject 的子类
AnyObject, or a subclass of NSObject, because they
的参数里传入它们， 因为他们
are bridged to classes that inherit from NSObject,
都被桥接到了 NSObject的子类里。
because NSString, NSArray, and
因为 NSString ，NSArray 和
NSDictionary all inherit from NSObject.
NSDictionary 全都继承自 NSObject 。
So, that means Strings, Swift Strings,
所以 String， 也就是Swift的字符串，
can be the keys in a Dictionary, an NSDictionary,
可以作为 NSDictionary 的键，
even though it requires NSObject, okay?
尽管要求键是 NSObject 类型的。
And of course, all three of them can be values,
当然，它们3个也可以作为字典的值，
because, even though they're not really objects,
因为，尽管他们不是对象，是 struct ， 但是他们桥接
they are structs, they are bridged to things that can be. Okay?
到 Objective-C 的东西可以作为值。
So, it is okay to pass a String or
所以，在需要传入 AnyObject 传入
an Array to AnyObject.
String 或者 Array 都没问题。
You won't even notice this bridge isn't bridging 99% of the time.
你在99%的时候都见不到这种桥接，
It just happens automatically.
它们都是自动的。
But I just wanted you to know that's going on, so
我只是想让你们知道背后发生了什么，
you don't get kinda confused when you start
这样在你们见到 NSString 或者 NSArray 的时候就
seeing NSString, NSArray, what's going on, okay?
不会感到疑惑了。
They're just being automatically bridged for you.
它们都是自动桥接过来的。
All right.
So, we talked about AnyObject last time,
上次我们讲过了AnyObject。
and now I'm gonna talk about a use of AnyObject,
现在我们要讲 AnyObject 的一个用处。
which is called Property List.
这就是 Property List 。
So, Property List is not a type or
Property List 并不是任何一种类型，
anything like that, it's just a term that we use.
它属于一种工具类的东西。
And the definition of that term is, it's in AnyObject,
它的定义是，
a Property List is AnyObject, that is known to be,
Property List 表面上是 AnyObject ， 但是在
behind the scenes, one of those six classes.
后台，它是 NSString
NSString, NSArray,
NSArray，
NSDictionary, NSNumber, NSData and NSDate.
Or bridged to with Swift, okay?
这六种类型中的一种，或者是它们桥接到Swift里的版本。
So, why do we define this Property List thing?
我们为什么要用 Property List 呢？
It's in AnyObject.
它属于 AnyObject
It's kind of unwieldy, because you have to do a lot,
它看起来非常笨重，因为我们需要用 is 或者 as 做
a fair amount of casting, ising and asing, cuz
大量的类型转换，因为要使用 AnyObject，
AnyObject, of course, to use it, we have to kinda cast it.
我们就要进行类型转换。
And so, why do we have this thing?
所以说，我们为什么要用它？
Two reasons really.
实际上有两个原因。
One, Property List is used to pass data around blind.
第一， Property List 要用来隐式的传递数据。
It's like a cookie, right? In a browser.
就好像浏览器里的cookie一样。
It's kind of this just bundle of data,
它们是只有创建者才知道如何
that only the creator of it knows how to interpret it,
解释它们的一组数据。
because only they know what Strings, Arrays,
因为只有创建人才知道里边到底是 String， Array
Dictionaries, and stuff are in there.
Dictionary 还是别的什么。
But to everyone else it,
但是对于其他人来说
just looks like AnyObject, so they don't know what it is.
它们就是 AnyObject ，但不知道具体是什么。
So, all they can do, is pass it around to other things.
所以他们能做的就是把它传给其他人。
So, it's good for blind data passing, the other thing is,
这是隐式数据传送的好处。另一个原因是
a Property List can be used as generic data structures, okay?
Property List 可以用于泛型的数据结构。
Since it's got Arrays, and
因为它可以是Array，
Dictionaries, and Numbers, and Dates, and all that in there.
Dictionary， Number， Date，都有可能。
You can turn a data structure, like your r-ops stack,
你可以把一个数据结构变成一个泛型的数据结构，就像你的
in the CalculatorBrain, it has op enums in there,
CalculatorBrain类里面的opStack，
that's not a generic data structure, but
它有一个叫做op的枚举，它不是泛型的
we can turn it into a generic data structure, for example,
但是我们可以把它改成泛型的。
and then do things with it like write it out to disk, or
泛型的数据结构可以用来写入磁盘，
send it over the network, or things like that.
或者通过网络传送。
So, those are the two main reasons we use Property List.
以上就是使用Property List的两个主要原因。
And, a really good use of Property List in
Property List 在 iOS里另外一个很好的用处
iOS is NSUserDefaults.
就是 NSUserDefaults。
So, NSUserDefaults is like a really tiny little database,
NSUserDefaults 就像一个微型的数据库。
and it only knows how to store Property Lists.
它只会存储Property List
Okay?
And it's really for things like settings, and
存储那些诸如设置，
preferences, stuff like that.
参数等等的东西。
You would never, it's not high performance,
由于它的性能不高，
you would never use it for big things like images or
所以千万不要用它存一些图片什么的比较大的数据，
anything like that, just Property Lists, you know,
只用来存 Property List，你懂的
Dates and Strings and Doubles, and things like that.
日期，字符串，数字什么的。
It can store and retrieve any Property List, and
它可以像字典一样存储和
it just stores it like a Dictionary,
导出Property List，
as if the NSUserDefaults thing itself is a Dictionary.
NSUserDefaults本身就是一个字典。
And, it can store the whole Property List,
它可以存储所有的Property List。
like setObject forkey: , that first method you see there.
比如 setObject forkey:， 就是你们在那看到的第一个方法。
And, repeat, retrieve all Property List,
然后，重复，取回所有的Property List。
or, it can just do little tiny pieces of Property List,
或者，它可以只处理Property List中的一小部分。
like it has a method set Double,
比如，它有个方法 set Double，
that will just set a Double for a certain key.
这将为某一 key 设置一个 Double 值。
Okay? So,
所以，
it's like a Dictionary in it's key value, but
它像一个有 key value 的字典，但
it only stores Property List.
它只存储Property List。
And, the big thing about the way it stores them,
最大的不同是，它存储这些属性，
is that it persists when your app is gone, okay?
当你的app关闭时，它永久保存这些数据。
So, you know,
你们知道的，
normally, a Dictionary is stored in the heap.
一般的，一个字典存储在堆中。
As soon as your app quits, it's gone.
只要你的 app 退出了，它就没了。
But this, stays around, so
但这个，保留着，所以
that when your app launches the next time,
当你的 app 在下次启动时，
all the data's still there.
所有的数据都在。
So, that's why it's kind of like a database, but
因此，这就是为什么它像个数据库，但
it's very small, okay?
它非常小。
For preference and settings.
为了性能和设置，
Here's how you use NSUserDefaults.
这是你要怎么使用 NSUserDefaults。
You use this type method in NSUserDefaults called
你在 NSUserDefaults 中使用这类方法
standardUserDefaults.
standardUserDefaults。
This gives you an instance of an NSUserDefaults.
这给你一个 NSUserDefaults 的实例。
You're always gonna use
你总是使用同一个实例，
the same instances like a shared instance.
类似于一个共享实例。
You'll always to use the same one.
你总是使用同一个（实例）。
And then you just send it messages like, you know,
然后，你就发消息给它，比如，正如你知道的，
setObject forkey:, store this Property List, and
setObject forkey:，保存这个Property List。
getObject forkey: to get it back.
然后使用 getObject forkey:，获取它。
Now, the changes you make in there,
现在，你在那里做的改变，
are automatically saved, but, there is a method called
会自动保存。有一个方法叫
synchronize, which is kinda like save, which can force it,
synchronize，类似于 save，这个方法可以强制
to save out to disc.
保存数据到磁盘。
Why do you ever need synchronize when it
既然有自动保存，为什么你还需要
auto saves?
synchronize？
Well, in auto save, when things happen like you app
好吧，在自动保存中，当有些事情发生时，比如你的 app
stops being the front most app,
不再作为最前端的 app，
the user switched to another app.
用户转向使用其他 app。
So, your app is still there, but
因此，你的 app 还在那里运行，但是
it switched to the background.
变成后台运行了。
It'll save then.
那时它将保存数据。
So, it won't always save when you want, and
因此，它不会总是在你需要的时候保存数据，
especially when you're debugging, okay?
特别是当你调试的时候。
When you hit stop in the debugger,
当你在调试器中停止时，
it doesn't save, okay?
它并不保存数据。
And so, you probably wanna throw some synchronizes in
因此，你可能要放一些 synchronize，
there, to save this thing out,
以便把数据保存下来。
especially when you're debugging.
特别是当你调试的时候。
It's not really that expensive to synchronize,
synchronize 操作，代价并不高，
especially if there's not much data in there,
特别是它没有很多数据的时候。
which there shouldn't be, because it's small.
它也不应该有很多数据，因为它很小。
So, it can't hurt too much to throw them in there.
因此，使用 synchronize 方法并没有太大伤害。
Okay?
And yeah, synchronize return to Bool,
当然，synchronize 返回 Bool 值，
whether it failed or not.
表示它失败与否。
But if it failed, there's really not much you can do.
但如果它失败了，你也不能做太多事情，
So, a lot of times people don't even look at the return
因此，大多数时候人们甚至不检查 synchronize 的
values synchronize, they just synchronize, and they pray.
返回值，他们只是使用 synchronize，然后他们祈祷。
But, it's only not gonna save if like the disk is full or
但是，它只是在磁盘满了或者其他时候无法保存数据，
something, that virtually never happens.
但这些情况很少发生。
All right, so, I'm gonna do a little demo here.
我要做些 demo。
And show you a little more about Property List.
给你展示更多的 Property List。
And also AnyObject,
还有 AnyObject。
cuz you've never seen AnyObject in action.
你永远不会在 action 中看到 AnyObject。
And what we're gonna do, is add a property to our
我们将做的，是在我们的 CalculatorBrain
CalculatorBrain, which gets its program.
添加一个属性，这个属性获取它的 program。
Okay?
So, our CalculatorBrain has a program, especially your
所以我们的 CalculatorBrain 有一个 program，特别是你们的
versions, where you added variables to it.
版本，当你们在其中添加变量。
It's got this kind of program,
它会有这样的 program，
it's almost like a little computer program.
它几乎像一个小的计算机程序。
You can execute that program, set its variables, it's great.
你可以执行这个程序，设置变量，这很好。
So, it would be nice if we could get that program.
如果我们能得到这个 program 会很棒。
But we don't wanna reveal our internal data structure, and
但我们并不想暴露我们内部的数据结构，
there's nothing anyone can do with that program.
这样任何人就不能在这个 program 上做任何事。
So, we're really just getting it as a cookie.
实际上我们的做法是像一个 cookie 一样来获取它。
And the only thing you can do with it, is give it back
你能做的唯一事情，把它返回给
to the CalculatorBrain, or another CalculatorBrain in
CalculatorBrain，或者将来的其他 CalculatorBrain，
the future, and then say, evaluate.
然后，调用 evaluate()
Okay, so you see the value of having this?
你们看到这样做的价值没？
So, basically getting the program out of
基本上就是，从 CalculatorBrain 中获取 program，
the CalculatorBrain and send it back.
然后把它送回去。
But we're gonna return it as a Property List.
但我们将以 Property List 的形式返回。
It's gonna be AnyObject.
它会是 AnyObject。
People are gonna look at this var, and
人们将查看这个变量，
it's gonna be of type AnyObject, and
它会是 AnyObject 类型，
all they can do is get it, and then set it back.
他们能做的是 get 它，然后 set 回去。
Okay?
So, what would that look like?
这会是什么样的？
Let's go over here to our Calculator.
让我们到我们的 Calculator 里来。
So, I've gone much bigger font here.
我已经在这里调了更大的字体。
Hopefully everybody, is this big enough?
希望每个人（能看到），这个够大吗？
Yeah?
Okay.
All right.
So, this is Calculator as I last left it.
这个是我上次留下的 Calculator。
It doesn't have your enhancements to it for
它没有你们为变量的改进。
the variables.
And I'm just gonna add a var here.
我就要再这里加一个 var。
A public var.
一个 public 的 var。
Okay?
Called program, and
叫做 program，
it's gonna be type AnyObject, but I'm gonna put comment here
这个会是 AnyObject 类型，但我要在这注释下，
that says guaranteed to be a Property List.
要保证是个 Property List。
So, the callers know that this is a Property List.
这样调用者知道这是个 Property List。
So, for example, they could put it into NSUserDefaults.
例如，他们可以把它放入 NSUserDefaults。
Or they could write it out to disc.
或者他们可以将这个写入磁盘。
I haven't taught you how to write it out to disc, but
我还没教你们怎么把这个写入磁盘。
you can do it.
你们能够做的。
So, they could do that with it,
他们可以那样做。
cuz they know it's a Property List, okay?
他们知道它是个 Property List。
So, this is going to be a computed property.
这是个 computed property。
Okay, so we're gonna have a get and a set.
我们将有一个 get 和一个 set。
And when the get,
当 get 时，
we're just gonna get some sort of Property
我们将获取代表我们内部数据结构的某个
List representation of our internal data structure.
Property List。
And when you set, we're gonna take that Property List and
当你 set 时，我们将得到 Property List 并且
turn it back into our private representation.
把它放回我们的私有代表。
So, the get,
这个 get，
how are we gonna represent ourselves as a Property List
这是我们怎么将我们自己表现为一个 Property List，
because this is really our internal data structure here,
因为这实际上是我们内部数据结构，
it's Array of op, op is an enum,
是个 op 数组，op 是枚举类型，
clearly enums are not NSDates, or NSStrings, or NSArrays.
显然，枚举不是 NSDates，也不是 NSStrings 或 NSArrays。
So, we can't just return this thing, okay?
我们不能只是返回这个东西，
Cuz that's not a Property List.
因为它不是一个 Property List。
So, we need to return some sort of Property List.
我们必须返回某种 Property List。
And I'm gonna return an Array of Strings.
我将返回一个 String 数组。
And the String is either gonna be the symbol of an op,
这个 String 是某个 op 的符号，
in which case I will look it up in knownOps, or
这个 op 我可以在 knownOps 中找到，或者
the String will be an numeric representation of
这个 String 会是个数字字符串，代表
the String of the operand rather.
操作数。
Right? The Double will
对吧，Double 将转换成
turn into a String.
一个 String。
Which I happened to have a var that does exactly that.
刚好我有一个变量正好可以处理这个。
Okay? This turns an enum op,
这将一个 op 枚举变成
into a String.
一个 String。
And I know how to turn it back.
我知道怎么把它变回来。
Because I know how to use a number formatter to turn
因为我知道怎么使用一个 number formatter 来把一个
the String of a operand back into a Double and
操作数字符串变成一个 Double。
obviously I know how to look up binary and
显然我也知道怎么在 knownOps 中
uniary operations in our knownOps.
查找二元和一元操作符。
Okay?
So, we could say something along these lines.
我们可以在这几行里写一些东西
Our get, I'm gonna show you a much better get in a second,
我们的 get，我马上给你演示一个更好的 get，
but one way we could do our get is we could just say,
实现 get 的一种方式是：
we could make a returnValue that is going to be
定义一个 returnValue，它的类型是
an Array of String.
Array
Okay, in fact let's just create an empty Array of
实际上，我们只是创建一个空的字符串数组，
String here, and then we can just go through our ops,
然后我们可以在我们的 opStack 中遍历我们的操作符，
in our opStack here, and for each op,
对于每一个操作符，
we can just say returnValue.append, an op's description.
我们可以使用 returnValue.append，将一个操作符的描述
On to the end of it, and then we could return, returnValue.
附加在它（returnValue）的后面，然后我们可以返回 returnValue。
Right, makes sense, I just my internal data structure into
懂了吗？我刚刚把我的内部数据结构转变成一个
a Property List, because this is a Property List.
Property List，因为这是一个 Property List。
Notice I can return, this through AnyObject,
注意我可以通过 AnyObject 返回。
because Arrays are bridged, and
因为 Arrays 是桥接好的，
NSArray which happens to be an object.
NSArray 恰好是一个 object，
Okay.
But this is an awful lot of code for this.
但这里这么多行代码，太可怕了。
We can actually do this in one line of code, okay?
实际上，我们可以仅使用一行代码
So if you paid attention in my last lecture, you'll remember
如果你们注意我上次讲的课，你们就会记得
that I told you about this function called map.
我跟你们说过，这个叫做 map 的函数。
And I can actually just return my opStack mapped,
实际上我可以直接返回 opStack.map
so that each element description is returned.
这样每个元素的描述都返回了。
So I don't need any of this, okay?
因此我不需要这里的任何一行代码。
So everyone understand this line of code right here?
每个人都理解了这行代码了吧。
This is just a little closure that gets the opportunity to
这仅仅是一个闭包，它转化 opStack 内的
convert every single thing inside opStack,
每个单一的东西，
which is an op, these are ops, into a String and it takes
也就是将操作符，这些都是操作符，转换成字符串，
this String and maps them all and returns a new Array.
然后得到这个字符串，然后将它们所有都映射，最后返回一个新的数组。
Okay?
So when you start getting familiar with Swift and
当你们开始熟悉 Swift，
what it can do,
和 Swift 能做的事情。
you'll start realizing a lot of things that take five or
你就开始意识到很多需要五六行代码处理的东西，
six line of code, you can just do them in one.
现在你只需要一行。
Okay, but it does take some experience.
但这需要一定的经验。
So now let's talk about going the other way.
现在让我们谈谈其他方式，
So now we have, someone gives us back our program.
现在有人给我们返回 program，
We wanna load our opStack back up.
我们想加载上我们的 opStack，
Well the first thing we wanna make sure is that the thing
第一件我们需要确认的事情是
they're giving us back is an Array of these symbols.
他们给我们的是这些符号的数组。
Because they could just give me junk,
因为他们可能给我们没用的东西。
because it's AnyObject they could set it to anything.
这是个 AnyObject，他们可以给它设置任何值。
So, I, I want to make sure that's what it is.
我需要确认这是什么。
So what I'm going to do,
我将要做的是，
I'm going to let opSymbols equal newValue, right?
输入 opSymobls = newValue，
newValue remember we are in the setter here.
newValue 记得我们在 setter 里。
So, newValue is the newValue which is in AnyObject.
这个 newValue 是 AnyObject 的。
As an Array of String, because that's what it has to be.
as Array，因为它必须是一个 Array 才行。
If this thing that they passed in is not an Array of String,
如果他们传递的不是字符串数组，
I don't know what to do with it.
我就不知道怎么处理。
So really here what I wanna do is, if let as question mark,
所以这里我想做的是， if let as?
because they could pass me anything.
因为他们可能传给我任何东西，
And so, here I'm using the as to make sure this AnyObject
所以这里我使用 as 以确保他们传递过来的 AnyObject
they pass me is actually and Array of Strings, okay?
确实是个字符串数组。
If it is, now I can convert back, so
如果是，我就可以转化回来，
I'm gonna create something called my newOpStack which
我将创建一个 newOpStack，
is just gonna be an Array of ops and I'm just gonna go for
它是一个操作符数组。我将遍历这个
each opSymbol in this opSymbols.
opSymbols 里的每个 opSymbol。
opSymbols is this thing right here, that's the Array,
opSymbols 是这个东西，这是 Array
that's the newValue, the AnyObject converted
这是 newValue，AnyObject 转换成了
into an Array of Strings, okay?
Array 类型，明白了吗？
So for each one if I can find a known op,
所以对于每一个 opSymbol
that matches that symbol then this must be an op,
在 knownOps 中找到对应的 op
and so I will just add that op
那么我就可以将
to, to my stack, otherwise I'm gonna see
那个 op 加至我的 newOpStack 中
if I could turn that String into an operand, and I'm gonna
否则我将尝试把字符串转换成一个操作数
do that with if let operand equal NSNumberFormatter.
这里我可以输入 if let operand = NSNumberFormatter()
Okay, numberFromString, I'm gonna pass it
NSNumberFormatter().numberFromString(...)
this opSymbol that I got out of that Array it gave me.
括号里的参数我将把 opSymbol 传进去
I'm going to use Optional Chaining here and
这里我将使用 Optional Chaining 并且
put a question mark, then doubleValue, okay.
放一个问号在这里，然后 .doubleValue
Remember Optional Chaining, if you have an expression like
记住，Optional Chaining 就是，如果你有一个像这样的表达式
this, this whole expression, and if anything along the way
那么整个表达式中任意一个
returns nil then this whole expression will return nil.
返回了 nil 的话，那么整个表达式将返回 nil
If you put a question mark after that term.
我在这里放置了一个问号
So, numberFromString can return nil if this is
那么如果给 numberFromString 传一个不能被解释成一个数字的 String
not a String, that can be interpreted as a number.
它就会返回 nil
So by putting a question mark here it says, okay?
所以这里我放置一个问号的意思是
If that's nil than just return nil back to here.
如果这个表达式返回 nil，则 operand 也将是 nil
Otherwise keep going and send it doubleValue.
如果不返回 nil，那么 operand 设置成表达式返回值的 doubleValue
So this operand is either going to not get set,
这个 operand 要么不被设值
because of the if let, or it's going to be a Double,
因为有 if let 的存在，要么它将成为一个 Double
which is what this doubleValue comes out of here.
也就是这里出现 doubleValue 的原因
Okay, so that's kind of explaining from last week how
好的，这就是上周我们讲的
we did this number formatter thing.
使用 number formatter 的知识
So in this case,
在这里
I can just append onto the end of it that a new op.
我只需要追加一个新的 op
So, we'll say dot operand with that operand.
我们输入 .Operand(operand)
So we're just putting a new op on there.
这样我们就追加了一个新的 op
So now I've built a new opStack using all those Strings,
现在我使用了所有的那些字符串创建了一个 newOpStack
and I can just return that new opStack.
这里我将返回这个 newOpStack
Not return it, sorry.
喔，这里不是返回
I'm gonna set my opStack equal to that new op
而是将 opStack = newOpStack
Stack, okay?
明白了吗？
That's it.
就这些
Any questions about that?
对此有什么疑问吗？
>>Property List?
- [学生提问]
Like that's just because.
>> This is documentation,
这是文档
this is a public thing, it's not private, and I'm just
这是一个 public 的东西，不是 private 的
documenting to anyone who's using it that this is true.
这是提供给任何使用我代码的人的文档
I can document this even better using a typealias.
我能够用 typealias 更好地整理我的代码文档
So you can basically have a typealias,
你仅仅需要输入 typealias
which is an alias for a type.
typealias 是一个类型的替身
It's just a way of another type, and
是其他类型的一个替身
I could have a typealias called PropertyList,
输入 typealias PropertyList = AnyObject
which is equals AnyObject.
Then I could have this type be PropertyList, okay?
接下来我就可以让 program: AnyObject 中的 AnyObject 成为 PropertyList 类型，明白了吗？
So I just created PropertyList as an alias for AnyObject, so
这里我创建了 PropertyList 类型，它是 AnyObject 的一个替身
someone looking at this is gonna go,
当别人看到这里的时候
whoa, what the heck is PropertyList?
他会有一个疑问，究竟什么是 PropertyList
Now they're going to look at this typealias, and
然后他们会回头看到这个 typealias
say, oh, that's AnyObject, but they're really going to
然后知道，那是 AnyObject，但是他们会明确知道
understand that I'm returning the Property List to them, and
我将返回一个 Property List 给他们
the reason is Property List, again, so
原因还是 Property List
I can throw it again as user defaults or whatever, okay?
我可以把它用作 NSUserDefaults 或者其他东西, 明白了吗？
But otherwise, it's only good, the only thing it's good for
但是它只有在
is giving it back to me to reset my program in
将来返回给我以重置 program 的时候才有用
the future; that's all this thing is good for.
这个东西就是这一点有用
Now, you're gonna wanna add this to your assignment for
现在，你们大概希望把这个加到你们的
assignment three, okay?
作业三中
So, all right, back to slides.
好的，回到我们的幻灯片中
I'm not gonna, I don't have time to really run this
我并没有足够的课堂时间运行这个
unfortunately due to in test code because we are
因为这个代码可能还需要调试，
schedule constraint here.
可是我们的时间表有限制
So let's go back to here, continue.
让我们继续
All right, so now let's talk about, new thing here,
继续讨论一些新东西
which is views, okay, totally new topic.
Views，全新的话题
A view, that is to say,
一个 view
a subclass of the class UIView in iOS
iOS 中 UIView 类的一个子类
represents a rectangular area on the screen.
表示了屏幕上的一个长方形的区域
That defines a coordinate space to draw in, and
定义了一个坐标系空间来绘图
also to handle touch events, okay?
和处理触摸的操作，明白了吗？
That's what a view is, and you are going to learn today,
这就是 view，你们今天要学的
how to make your own views.
如何制作你们自己的 views
The views are hierarchical, so,
views 是有层次的
views are within views are within views.
这就意味着 views 可以在 views 中
Any view only has one superview.
但是任何一个 view 都只能有一个 superview
Right, it's only contained directly in one view.
这也就意味，一个 view 是直接包含在另一个 view 中的
But, it can have any number of subviews.
但是一个 view 可以有多个 subview
So in our Calculator, we had a top level view,
在我们的计算器程序中，我们有一个最高层的 view
which I'm gonna talk about in a moment,
这个一会儿我会讲到
and then we had a lot of subviews, all the buttons,
接下来我们有一大堆的 subviews，都是按钮
the labels, those are all UIView subclasses.
和标签，它们是 UIView 的子类
Okay, so we made a whole bunch.
所以我们将会用到一大堆
A bunch of subviews in that view.
一大堆的 subviews，在最高层的 view 中
But you can go even deeper.
但是你可以更深入地研究它
It's hierarchical multi-layer.
这是个有层次的 multi-layer
We can go as deep as we want.
我们想研究多深入都可以
The two, you can see the two properties there for
在这里，你看到这两个 properties
getting your superview.
用来获取你的 superview
Notice it returns a Optional, because you
注意，它返回一个 Optional，这是因为
can have a view that's not currently on screen.
你可以拥有一个当前不在屏幕中的 view
It's not currently in the view hierarchy so that can be nil.
不在当前 view 层次结构中的 view 都会是 nil
Your subviews, I show Array of UIView there.
还有一个属性是 subviews，这里我写的是一个 UIView 数组
Actually the subview's property is an Array of AnyObject,
实际上这个 subview property 是一个 AnyObject 数组
again for historical reasons, but
因为一些历史性的原因，不过
there will always be UIViews in there.
元素始终都是 UIView 对象
So don't even worry about that, okay?
所以不用担心，okay?
And usually in this class on the the slides,
在这门课的幻灯片中，
if something's an Array of AnyObject,
如果看到一个 AnyObject 数组
if there's gonna be a certain kind of thing in there,
那就是里面肯定有某种特定的东西
I'll say, Array of the certain kind of thing.
换言之，由某种特定的对象组成的数组
But when you write your code, then,
但是当你编写自己的代码时
obviously, you might see, oh, that's Array of AnyObject, and
很明显，你将会知道这是个 AnyObject 数组
that's again, the bridging will work here,
再一次，桥接起作用了
automatically, so, no worries there. UIWindow.
这一切都是自动完成的，不需要你操心。UIWindow
There is a certain thing called a UIWindow.
有这么一个东西叫 UIWindow
It's a subclass UIView but it has no meaning in iOS.
它是 UIView 的子类，但是在 iOS 开发中你不需要关心
There is a UIWindow it's at the very,
在每一个设备屏幕上都会有一个 UIWindow
very, very top of each device screen but
它在最高层上面
you never send it any messages really.
但是你不会向它发送任何消息
You don't interact with it.
你不跟它交互
It's all about views.
在 iOS 中你只要关心 views
On a desktop windows matter.
但是在桌面环境中，UIWindow 就很关键
But on iOS, it's all about views, okay?
再次强调，在 iOS 中你只要关心 views，明白了吗？
So don't worry about UIWindow.
不要操心 UIWindow
This hierarchy of views, subviews and
views 的层次结构，subviews 和
superviews, is created usually, graphically.
superviews 通常不需要通过代码来创建
You can drag things out in the StoryBoard.
你可以直接从 StoryBoard 中拖出来这些组件
You can drag views inside other views to
你可以在其他 views 中拖入 views
create your hierarchy.
来创建你自己的层次结构
But you can do it in code as well.
但是这并不是说不能用代码来创建这些东西
It's pretty rare to do it in code, but you can.
很少人用代码创建图形部分，但是你可以这么做
There's two methods here addSubview and
这里有两个方法：addSubview 和
removeFromSuperview, addSubview is sent to
removeFromSuperview，addSubview 是
the prospective superview.
向预期的 superview 发送的消息
In other words to the place you wanna add your,
换言之，superview 是你想添加你的 view 的地方
this view into.
And removeFromSuperview is sent to the view that you
同样的，removeFromSuperview 是
want to remove.
向你想要移除的 view 发送的消息
So these are sent to different people,
这两个消息发送给不同的对象
okay, removeFromSuperview means remove yourself from
removeFromSuperview 意味着把“你”自己从 superview 中
your superview.
移除
So, where does the view hierarchy start?
那么 view 的层次结构从那里开始呢？
Where is the kind of the root,
它肯定有一个根节点
the top level of this hierarchy, and
在层次结构的最顶上
the answer is very simple, but, for some reason,
答案很简单，但是因为某些原因
students have a very difficult time understanding this one.
学生们会很难理解这个概念
There is a property in your UIView Controller
在你们的 UIView Controller 中有一个 property
called view, and
名字叫 view
it is the top level view in the scene in the StoryBoard.
这就是你们在 StoryBoard 场景中的最高层次的 view
All right. So you have this StoryBoard.
这里你有这个 StoryBoard
You've got your scene that we've seen like your
你有一个场景跟 Calculator 差不多的场景
Calculator one.
The top level one, the place where you're going to add
在视图层次中最高层（你将要添加
your top level views, is called view in your View Controller.
你顶层 views 的地方）在 View Controller 中叫做 view
It's just a property in UIView Controller.
它就是一个在 UIViewController 中的 property
So it really couldn't be simpler, okay?
不能够更简单了吧
Sometimes students they just forget that's there and
有时学生们忘记了 UIViewController 中还有这么一个 view
ask how do I add something to my StoryBoard?
然后问：我怎么在我的 StordBoard 中添加东西呢？
You know in code or something like that.
你想要从代码中实现
Well you just you add it to the view of
你只需要把它加入 UIViewController
your UIViewController, okay?
的 view 中，明白了吗？
So, let's talk about initializing a view.
接下来让我们讨论一下初始化一个 view
As usual, as I've kind of recommended, you probably want
通常我建议，不要做初始化
to avoid doing an initializer, if you can.
尽可能不要
So, to initialize any properties in
这里，在你的 view 中初始化
your view hopefully using equals or
一些 properties 可以使用 = 来赋值
some of the other ways we've talked about doing it.
或者我们说过的其他方法实现
But, in UIView it's slightly more likely that you
但是，在 UIView 中有一点点相似的地方是
might want to have an initializer.
你可能需要一个 initializer
So it's a slightly complicated thing.
通常这个有一点点复杂
Only slightly.
不过只有一点点
In that UIView has two initializers you
UIView 中有两个 initializers 是
have to deal with.
你需要处理的
And that's because UIViews can be created in
那是因为 UIView 可以由两种不同的方法
two different ways.
来创建
In code by just saying UIView and
在代码中你会写 UIView(frame: CGRect)
this frame initializer, which is just the frame in the superview,
这个 frame 就是 superview 的 frame
coordinate system where this view is gonna live.
它是一个坐标系，这个 view 将在这个坐标系里面
But then there's also this init with coder.
还有一个是 init(coder: NSCoder)
And I'm not gonna talk about coders and
这里不打算讲 coders
archiving and all that.
和归档的那些东西
But that is the initializer that is called when the view
但是在 Storyboard 中初始化的时候会
comes out of a StoryBoard.
调用 init(coder: NSCoder) 方法
So, if you create a view by dragging on a StoryBoard,
所以，你在 StoryBoard 中拖入一个 view
its initializer is this coder thing, okay?
它的初始化方法就会是 init(coder: NSCoder)，明白了吗？
So, if you want, if you absolutely have to use
如果你想要，如果你不得不
an initializer to initialize something in your UIView,
在你的 UIView 中使用一个 initializer 时
you're gonna want to implement both of these things.
你就要实现这两个方法
And I recommend this kind of format here.
这里我推荐的格式是
Where you override init with frame there.
当你在这里 override init(frame: CGRect)
That is a designated initializer in UIView.
这是一个UIView 的 designated initializer
And then, there's actually a required initializer,
接下来，还有一个 requried 的 initializer
which is the decoder one.
也就是 decoder 方法
So if you implement the init with frame you have to
如果你实现了 init(frame: CGRect) 方法
implement the coder one, it's required,
你必须同时实现 init(coder: NSCoder)，
cuz as soon as you implement the init with frame,
因为只要是你实现了 init(frame: CGRect)
you'll no longer inherit all of your designated
你就不再继承所有的 designated initializers
initializers you won't inherit the init with the coder.
同样你不再继承 init(coder: NSCoder)
So, basically implement them both, and
所以，简单来说就是实现这两者
then just factor your initialization code into some
然后将这两个 initializer 分解成
setup method or something, and call that, okay?
setup 方法或者其他的方法，然后调用分解出来的方法，明白了吗？
So, that's only if you absolutely have to
当且仅当你不得不
have an initializer.
自己实现一个 initializer 才这么做
All right, there's another alternative to initializing.
好了，还有一个初始化的办法
Which is if you can wait until the initialization is finished
那就是，如果你可以等初始化完成
but you want something really early in the view's life,
但你真的需要在这个视图构造好之前做一些东西的话
you can implement this method awakeFromNib.
你可以实现 awakeFromNib 方法
But that only works for
但是只有 Storyboard 中的视图
views that come out of a StoryBoard, okay?
才会调用这个方法，记住了吗？
awakeFromNib means I just awoke from coming out of
awakeFromNib 表示，我刚刚从 Storyboard 中
a StoryBoard.
被加载出来了
So now you can initialize me.
你可以做一些初始化操作
So it's a little bit limited, because it only is good for
不过这个方法使用很有局限性
views that come out of a Storyboard.
因为它只是针对 Storyboard 中的视图
But it is an alternative.
但是这确实是另外一种方法
Now okay, so
好的
that's all I'm going to say about that actually.
以上是关于视图初始化方面的内容
Now let's go on to how do we.
现在我们来看看怎样在视图中
Draw and handle events in this rectangular area.
绘制和处理触摸事件
Well we need a coordinate system to work in.
我们需要一个坐标系来完成这些功能
So there's some data structures I'm going to
所以我先会大致介绍一些
show you real quick to get us started here, that we're
我们在绘制和处理触摸事件中
gonna use when we're drawing and handling events.
需要用到的数据结构
First of all, all coordinates are gonna be CGFloat.
首先，所有的坐标系的单位都是 CGFloat
Okay, CGFloat is a type in Swift struct.
是的，CGFloat 在 Swift 中是结构体
And always use CGFloat when you're drawing or
记住，在绘制和处理触摸事件的时候
handling events in a view.
我们都用 CGFloat 类型
Do not use Double.
不要用 Double 类型
Do not use Float.
也不要用 Float 类型
If you use those in your homework,
如果你在课后作业中使用 Double 和 Float 这些类型
you're gonna get dying, okay?
这在程序里是行不通的
CGFloat.
只能用 CGFloat
Now Doubles and
你可以通过初始化方法
Floats can be converted to a CGFloat using the initializer.
将 Double 和 Float 类型转换成 CGFloat 类型
CGFloat has initializer for Float and Double.
你也可以通过 CGFloat 的初始化方法
that you can pass and turn into a Float.
把 CGFloat 类型转换为 Double 或 Float 类型
But, you always want things to be into CGFloat when you're
但是你在坐标系中操作的时候
working in the coordinate system, okay?
你希望所有的东西都是 CGFloat 类型，对吧？
Now, there's a couple other structures that
这里还有一些比较重要的
are important here.
结构体
One is CGPoint.
一个是 CGPoint
It's just two Floats, X and Y.
它是由 x 和 y 两个 Float 类型组成的
Just defines a point in the coordinate system.
它用来定义坐标系中的一个点
Couldn't be simpler.
不能更简单了
Okay? And there's also CGSize,
然后，另外一个是 CGSize
just defines a width and
它在坐标系中定义
a height in the coordinate system.
一个长和一个宽
Okay, so these are just simple structs.
是的，就是一些简单的结构体而已
That's all they are, structs.
他们都是结构体
I don't know, certainly Point,
我不太确定，但貌似
I don't think has any other methods on it or anything.
CGPoint 并没有其他的方法
Size, maybe, I don't think so, though.
CGSize 可能有，不过我也不太确定
But these two are combined, the points and
当 CGSize 和 CGPoint 组合在一起的时候
the size, to CGRect.
就变成了 CGRect
So CGRect is struct that has a point and a size.
CGRect 是由一个 CGPoint 类型的 point 和一个 CGSize 类型的 size 组成的结构体
The point is the origin of the rect.
point 是这个矩形的原点
Upper left, which I'm going to talk about in a second.
也就是矩形左上角的点，我稍后会详细解释的
And then the size is the width and height.
然后 size 是矩形的宽和高
Now rect has a lot of methods on it, okay?
CGRect 有很多方法
Rect has things like minX,
比如说 minX
which is the left edge of the rect.
它表示矩形的左边界
Or midY, which is the midpoint of the rectangle vertically.
又比如说 midY，表示矩形垂直方向上的中点
Or intersects.
还有 intersects 方法
And you pass another Rect, and it'll tell you,
你传递另外一个矩形进去，它会返回一个布尔值
Boolean, whether it intersects that Rect, right?
来判断这两个矩形是否相交
The two Rects overlap.
也就是它们是否重叠
Or, intercept, which says, take this other Rect and
或者，intercept 方法可以创建一个
create a smaller rectangle,
更小的矩形
which is the intersection of those two Rects.
这个小矩形是由两个矩形交叉的部分
Or contains point.
还有一个 CGRect 的方法叫 contains
Okay, we passed a point and
就是我们传递一个 CGPoint 类型的值进去
it'll tell you whether it contains that point.
它告诉你这个点是否在矩形中
So rect is this struct, but
所以，CGRect 这个结构体
it has a lot of cool methods in there.
有很多很有意思的方法
A whole bunch more.
一大堆的方法
You can just type a rect, type and
你只需要键入 CGRect
then a dot Xcode show you all the cool methods it has, okay?
然后输入一个点（表示方法调用），Xcode 会显示所有这些方法
All right, so those are the types of data types we're
好的，以上所有这些结构体
gonna use to talk about our coordinate system and
都是关于坐标系和在坐标系中操作
to write our code in coordinate system.
时所需要用的数据结构
So let's talk about the Views coordinate system itself.
接下来我们看看视图中的坐标系统
First of all, origin upper left.
首先，原点在左上角
Some of you might be used to origin lower left,
你或许遇到过原点在左下角的坐标系
like Cartesian coordinates,
比如笛卡尔坐标系
the origin is in the lower left.
它的原点就在左下角
But all this origin that you're using a view is in
但是你在使用一个视图的时候，它的坐标原点
the upper left.
都处于左上角
So, that means increasing Y is down the screen,
也就是说，Y 轴向下延伸
increasing X is across.
X 轴向右延伸
So, I put an example, 500 dot 35, 500 comma 35, over there.
比如这里有一个点（500，35）
It's 500 across, and only 35 down, okay?
它相对于左上角
From the upper left.
向右500单位距离，向下35单位距离，明白吗？
The units that we're talking about here are points
在这里我们用的单位是点
not pixels.
不是像素
Okay.
是的
Pick high, very high resolution displays have more
高分辨率的屏幕中，每一个点可能表示
than one pixel per point.
多个像素
Okay, 'cuz they are able to draw very find curves,
因为这么做可以用来绘制非常平滑的曲线
very fine text, et cetera.
和文本等（抗锯齿）
You don't usually care
你通常不需要留心
about the difference between points and pixels.
点和像素之间的区别
It's automatically handled for
因为在你绘制文本或者曲线的时候
you because you're doing things like drawing text or
这些东西会被自动处理，iOS 系统尽可能考虑
drawing an arc and the system automatically uses as much
一个点到底应该占多少个像素
pixels as it can to make things nice.
才能使绘制看上去更加完美
But occasionally you do care,
但有些特殊的时候，你需要注意这些区别
because maybe you're drawing something very finely detailed
特别是你需要处理和控制
and you want to control pixel boundaries.
非常精细的细节和像素边界的时候
And if you want to do that you can call this,
你可以访问你的视图中的一个属性
get this property in view called contentScaleFactor
这个属性的名字是 contentScaleFactor
and it will return the number of pixels per point.
它会返回给你每点占多少个像素的值
So on a retina display, that's gonna be 2.
在视网膜屏（Retina）中，一个点表示2个像素
On a non-retina display, that will be 1.
非视网膜屏中表示1个像素
It could be anything, though.
当然在其他屏幕中或许是任意的值
Okay?
明白吗？
So you shouldn't write your code assuming it's 2 or 1.
所以你在代码里，不能直接写死2或1
You should just write your code, get the contentScaleFactor
你在写代码的时候
and you'll know how many pixels per point.
应该通过获取 contentScaleFactor 属性来知道这个值
Okay?
记住了吗？
99% of the time, you don't have to worry about this, but
百分之九十九的情况下，你不需要担心这个问题，但是
in your assignment three, hint, hint, you might have to.
在课后作业3中，你可能需要处理这个问题
Okay.
好的
So what about the boundaries of where drawing happens.
那么，我们绘制区域的边界在哪里？
You've got this rectangular area.
你已经有一个矩形区域
Well, there's a very important property called bounds,
另外，有一个非常重要的属性，叫做 bounds
which is a CGRect, which describes the area you're
它是 CGRect 类型，它定义了坐标系中
drawing in in your own coordinate system.
的绘制区域
Okay? It's important that it's in
明白吗？需要特别注意的是
your own coordinate system.
绘制是相对于自身的坐标系
Because these views can be scaled and even rotated and
因为视图可以被拉伸，旋转
translated to other you know, coordinates systems.
或者变换等（父视图坐标系中）
But when you're using the bounds and
但是你用 bounds 属性的时候
you're drawing it yourself, you have this rectangle and
你是在自身坐标系绘制，你知道这个矩形
you know where it is.
的确切位置
Now the origin of your bounds usually is 0,0.
bounds 的原点通常是（0，0）
But you could define it to mean something else, for
但是你可以更改它
example, scroll views they define their origin to
比如，Scroll View 在滚动的时候会
be where they are in the thing they're scrolling,
更改它的原点为目前滚动到的位置
that's just what they define origin to be, but
这是 Scroll View 定义 bounds 原点的方式
90% of the time, your origin is just going to be 0,0.
但是百分之九十的情况下，你的 bounds 的原点是（0，0）
So, the width and
宽和高
height is what you're going to care about,
才是你需要关心的
how big a space am I drawing into.
我可以在多大的区域内绘制？
There are two other properties that often get confused with
这里还有两个容易和 bounds 混淆的属性
bounds, but don't let this happen to you.
我希望你不会混淆它们
One is center.
一个是 center
Center is the center of your view rectangle in your
center 是你自身视图矩形的中点
superview's coordinate system, not in yours.
不过它是相对于父视图的坐标系，而不是自身坐标系的
So if you write code that say, oh, I'm gonna start to
如果你这样写代码，我将在矩形中心
draw something in middle of my rectangle.
绘制一些东西
I'll get center.
我使用 center
Aah!
That's wrong.
这样就会出问题了
Okay? Center is in your super view.
明白了吗？center 是相对于父视图的坐标系
Center positions you.
center 定义你在父视图的位置
It has nothing to do with how you draw.
它和绘制操作没有关系
It just says where you are in your super view.
它仅仅用来在你父视图中定位
Same thing, frame, frame is a rectangle in your
同样，frame 是父视图坐标系中
super view's coordinate system that contains you.
用来包含子视图的一个矩形
Okay, it contains all of you, of your drawing.
是的，它包含子视图的所有区域，包括绘制部分
But it's in your super user coordinates systems so
但是它是相对于父视图的坐标系
it's only good to position you, not for drawing.
所以它只是用来定位子视图，与绘制无关
When you're drawing, you use bounds.
绘制的时候，你使用 bounds
To kind of give you a picture of this,
为了更形象地说明这个
as better like you might think that
你可以这样认为
the frame size is exactly the same as the bound size.
frame 的 size 和 bounds 的 size 总是相同的
Right, if it's a rectangle that contains my rectangle,
如果一个矩形要完全包含我
it must be exactly the same size.
它必须和我的尺寸一样大
But no, because view can be rotated.
但也有例外，因为视图可以被旋转
Okay? And
明白了吗？
if you rotate your view like this green view,
如果你像这个绿色视图这样，旋转你的视图
look how much bigger the frame is.
你可以看到，frame 要大的多
The rectangle that contains you is much bigger than you.
包含你的矩形，要比你自己大得多
Because you're tilted.
因为你是倾斜的
All right?
没问题吧？
Make sense?
清楚了吗？
So don't confuse frame and center, which are about
所以不要混淆了，frame 和 center 是用来定位视图的
positioning, with bounce which is your size and
而 bounds 是用来在视图自身的坐标系中
area that you're drawing into in your own coordinate system.
确定大小和区域的
Okay?
明白吗？
Okay, so creating views.
接下来，视图的创建
How do we create views?
我们怎样创建一个视图？
Most often views are created by dragging them out to
大部分的视图是直接
the Storyboard.
通过 Storyboard 生成的
That's 95% of the time.
大概百分之九十五都是这样
And af, but
但是
of course, your views aren't sitting in the Object Pallet,
官方视图可能不能满足你的需要
there's buttons and sliders, but there's no your view.
这里有按钮，滑条等，但是可能没有你需要的视图
So you have to drag it out of generic view.
这时候，你就需要先拖一个通用的视图（UIView）
It's kind of at the bottom of the pallet and
就在控件区的底部
you just drag it out.
拖出来就可以了
Once you drag it out though,
一旦你拖出来这个视图后
you have to go to the Identity Inspector and change the class
你需要在它的 Identity Inspector 里
of that view that you dragged out, so that it's your class.
把对应的类修改你自己的实现类
Okay? So it's a two step process.
明白吗？需要两步来完成这个操作
You drag a view, your custom view out and then you change
先拖一个通用的视图出来
this class to view whatever your custom class is on rare
然后把对应的类改为你自己的类
occasion, you might create an instance of your view in code.
只有在很少情况下，你才需要用纯代码创建视图
Probably never in this class,
至少本课程范围内，你不需要这样做
maybe in your final project, although I doubt it.
大作业上可能会用到
You just do that using UIView's frame initializer.
你可以通过一个特殊的构造器
Right? So you just say
来通过代码创建一个视图
view equals UIView frame.
这里你输入 view = UIView(frame: ...)
You can even do UIView with no arguments and
甚至你也可以不传参数给这个构造器
it'll give you a CGRect to zero which is a frame zero
这样的话，它返回给你一个空视图（CGRectZero），也就是说这个视图的
size and width and
size 和 frame 都是0
then you could later set its frame to position the view.
稍后，你可以再设置这个视图的 frame 来确定位置
So here's an example of creating a view in code.
这里有一个使用代码创建视图的例子
I'm going to use UILabel.
我接下来要使用 UILabel 控件
UILabel is a subclass of UIView so I can send it.
UILabel 是 UIView 的一个子类，所以我可以使用带 frame 参数的构造器
UILabels parentheses frame.
UILabel(frame: ...)
So I just give it this frame which is kind of in
我传入一个 frame
the upper left.
这个 frame 会让视图设置在左上方的位置
Notice I've created this view but it's not on screen yet.
注意，我已经创建了这个视图，但是它并没有显示在屏幕上
Okay.
Assuming this code here is in a View Controller,
假设这里的代码是在一个 View Controller 里
I could then say view.addSubview.
我接下来可以输入 view.addSubview
Cuz remember view is a property in
还记得 view 是一个在我的 View Controller 中的一个属性吗？
my View Controller which is that top level view.
它指向了 View Controller 中最顶层的那个视图
And I could say add subview of the label and
这里我输入，view.addSubview(label)
boom, it'll appear on screen.
这样，这个视图就出现在屏幕上了
Okay? At 20,20 ,
在（20，20）的位置上
width 100, height 50.
宽度是100，高度是50
Okay?
明白了么？
So it is possible to create views in code.
所以可以完全通过代码来创建一个视图
We almost never do that in iOS.
不过 iOS 开发中几乎不这么做
We use Storyboard.
我们使用 Storyboard
Okay, so when do I wanna create my own UIView?
那么，什么时候我们会想创建一个自己的 UIView 呢？
Right?
嗯？
Well, when don't you want to?
换一个思路，什么时候我么你不想创建一个自己的 UIView
Well you don't want to if you want a button or a slider or
当你只是需要一个按钮或者 Slider 或者任何东西
anything where there's already an iOS view.
这些已经存在于 iOS 系统的控件库中的时候，你不需要自己创建一个 UIView
But if you want to do something that
但是如果你想要做一些
those things can't do, draw something special or
特别的事情，比如绘制一些其他图形
handle touch events like swipes and
或者想让触摸事件，例如 Swipes 和
taps and pinches, differently or for a different purpose.
Taps 以及 Pinches 手势，有着不同的处理方式
Then those things then you create your own custom view.
那么你这时候，你想要创建自己的 UIView
So, we're going to focus on drawing today, and
所以，我们今天将会专注于绘制
I'll do gestures in the next lec, in the next lecture.
然后在下节课我将会讲触摸手势识别相关的内容
To draw in your UIView,
在你的 UIView 中绘制时
all you need to do is override this method drawRect.
你需要重写 drawRect 方法
Okay, very simple method only takes one argument.
一个非常简单的方法，它只接受一个参数
In the code, it's actually called Rect, but
在代码中，这个参数实际上叫做 rect
I've renamed it to be regionThatNeedsToBeDrawn, so
但是我已经将它重新命名为 regionThatNeedsToBeDrawn
that people understand what that argument is.
这样人们就可以更好理解 rect 参数是什么意思
That argument is purely an optimization.
那个参数纯粹是起一个优化效果
It's just the system saying, hey, draw yourself and really,
这个参数告诉系统，当你绘图的时候
I only care about this rectangle of you.
我只是关心参数的这个区域
But you can draw your, the whole self if you want.
当然你可以绘制整个，整个你想要的视图区域
But this is the only rectangle I really care about.
但是只有这个矩形范围，才是我真正关注的
So if you had a View that knew how to draw parts of itself,
所以如果你有一个视图，而且视图知道如何去绘制它的部分区域
okay, then it could only draw the part that's in
那么这个方法只会绘制
this rectangle, but
参数这个矩形区域内的部分
you can completely ignore this rectangle if you want.
当然你可以完全忽略你想要的这个矩形范围
It's purely an optimization.
它纯粹的起一个优化效果
Okay?
明白了吗？
This is very important to understand,
下面这个概念是相当重要的
you never call drawRect, ever, never.
“永远不要调用 drawRect 方法”
Never.
永远不要
Okay?
If you call drawRect in your homework,
如果你在你的课后作业中调用了 drawRect 方法
you're going to be a major ding.
你会得到一个很糟糕的分数
Because I'm standing here in front of
因为我站在这里，站在
you with red text on my slide.
我 Slide 上的红色文字之前
Saying, never.
告诉你，永远不要这么做
Okay.
Do not call drawRect, drawRect is called by the system.
不要调用 drawRect 方法，drawRect 方式是被系统调用的
Okay?
明白了吗？
It's called by the system when your view needs to be redrawn.
当你的视图需要重新绘制时，它会自动被系统调用
How does the system know your needs,
那么你们会问，系统是怎样知道你需要重绘这个视图呢？
view needs to be redrawn?
重绘这个视图呢？
Because somebody called setNeedsDisplay on your view.
在你的视图里，有一个叫做 setNeedDisplay 的方法
And you can call it on yourself if you want.
如果你需要重绘视图的话，你可以调用它
If something has changed about your view, some property or
如果在你的视图中有内容发生变化时
something that would change the way it's drawn,
比如一些属性或者一些东西的改变
you call setNeedsDisplay on yourself,
你可以对自身调用 setNeedsDisplay 方法
eventually the system will call your drawRect.
最终，系统会在合适的时机调用你的 drawRect 方法
But it's got to set some things up first, okay.
但是首先，它会设置某些东西
There's other views around you.
在你周围有其他的视图
That it has to get organized.
它们必须先被组织起来
Okay, so never call drawRect, drawRect it's called for you.
所以，永远不要调用 drawRect，drawRect 会自动被系统调用的
When you call setNeedsDisplay, you can specify I
当你调用 setNeedsDisplay 的时候
really only need this rectangle redisplayed and
你可以指定，你只需要某个特定的范围来重绘
then obviously,
接下来
that rectangle's gonna show up in the argument to drawRect.
那块区域将会以参数形式传递给 drawRect 方法
Okay, but if multiple people call set in use display with
好的，如果当很多人在用不同的矩形范围上
different rectangles, probably the union of those
调用 setNeedsDisplay 的时候，可能这些区域的并集
rectangles might get called here one time for drawRect.
会作为参数被 drawRect 方法一次调用完成
Okay?
明白了么？
Make sense?
听懂了么？
All right.
So, how do you implement this, pow,
所以，你要怎样实现这个
all-powerful drawRect method?
无所不能的 drawRect 方法呢？
You can use, kind of a C-like, function-based API,
你可以使用，类似于 C 语言，基于函数的 API
called Core Graphics.
叫做 Core Graphics
That's what it's all based on.
它是所有图像绘制的基础
Or you can use a nice object-oriented, thing,
或者你可使用一种更高层次、面向对象的做法
called UIBezierPath, which is what we're gonna use,
叫做 UIBezierPath，这就是我们接下来要使用的
because we like object-oriented.
因为我们偏向于用一些高层次的 API
But since the underlying stuff core graphics is what
但是，因为涉及到图形绘制底层的东西
UIBezierPath is built on, I'm gonna kinda explain a little
我会介绍一些 Core Graphics 的概念
bit about the concepts of Core Graphics.
它是构建 UIBezierPath 的核心和基础
How one draws in Core Graphics.
一个东西是怎么样在 Core Graphics 中绘制的？
The first thing in Core Graphics that's important is,
在 Core Graphics 中第一件很重要的事是
you have to get a context to draw in.
你得拥有一个用来绘制的上下文（context）
Okay?
明白了吗？
So if you're printing you'll have a printing context.
如果你要 printing 那你得有一个 printing 的 context
If you're drawing on screen you'll have a draw on
如果你要在屏幕上绘制你得有一个
screen context, et cetera.
可以绘制的屏幕 context，等等
And inside drawRect, when you're drawRect is called by
在 drawRect 中，当你准备绘制时
the system, it sets up the drawing context for you.
系统会调用 drawRect 方法并且为你建立一个绘制的 context
So it's automatically set up,
所以它是自动建立的
and it's called the current context,
并且它被称为当前的 context
the current drawing context.
当前的绘制 context
And you can get it if you were using the C-API.
同时如果你使用 C-API 你也可以得到它
Or C-like APIs it's still Swift but it's functional.
或者C-like APIs 它仍然是 Swift 但是它是实用的
Function API, you can get it
API 函数，你可以得到他们
with this function UIGraphicsGetCurrentContext.
通过 UIGraphicsGetCurrentContext 方法
And it will return this cookie,
它将会返回到这个 cookie
it's just this magic cookie.
它只个令人惊奇的 cookie
You don't know what it is, but it is the context of drawing.
你不知道它是什么，但是它是绘制时的 context
Because all of the C-like functional API take
因为所有的 C-like 函数的 API
a context as an argument.
使用 context 作为参数
Okay, BezierPath doesn't do that no worries,
Okay，BezierPath 不会这样做，不用担心
but that one does.
但是那个会这么做
So the first thing you need is a context automatically set up
所以你需要做的第一件事是自动创建一个 context
for your when drawRect is called.
当你的 drawRect 被调用时
Then you create paths, you create paths with lines and
然后你创建路径，通过线条和
arcs and things like that.
弧线以及诸如此类的东西创建路径
Then you set the drawing attributes,
然后你设置绘制的属性
like the colors you want to draw in, the linewidths, and
比如你希望绘制的颜色，线条宽度
things like that, and
和类似于这些的东西
finally, you stroke and fill those paths.
最后你描边并且填充这些路径
Okay?
明白了么？
And you can do either, or, or both stroking and filling.
你可以做任意一个，或者同时做两个
So that is how, that is fundamentally how you draw.
因此这就是你绘制的基础
Things like drawing text is just the fonts know how to
类似于绘制文字之类的事情只是需要知道字体
have the perfect path to draw beautiful letters.
并且如何获得一个完美的路径来绘制漂亮的字母
And so, your stroking would outline the letters, and
所以，你的描边将描绘出字母的轮廓
filling fills in the letters, okay?
然后填充到字母的内部，明白？
So even drawing text, is just stroking and filling paths.
所以即使是绘制文字，也只需要描边和填充的路径
Okay? Now, UIBzierPath, this object-oriented
明白了么？现在，UIBzierPath，这个面向对象的
thing on top, it always draws in the current context,
东西在最上面，它通常在当前的 context 上绘制
you don't have to worry about context.
你不用担心这个 context
It has methods, to do things like line two, arch two,
它有很多方法，去做一些类似于两个线条，两个弧线的东西
to build the path.
用来建立路径
It also has methods for
它同样拥有很多方法
setting a lot of these attributes like linewidth and
用来设置很多属性例如线宽
things like that and it has methods to stroke and fill.
和一些类似的属性同时它还有很多方法去描边和填充
So combine all those Core Graphics things into one class.
所以将所有的 Core Graphics 放到一个类里
So let's look at UIBezierPath, and
让我们来看一下 UIBezierPath
how we would use it to draw a triangle, let's say.
和我们怎样使用它绘制一个三角形，比如说
First we create a path, so we just say, UIBezierPath.
首先，我们创建一个路径，比方说，UIBezierPath
There are other initializers for UIBezierPath but
有其他的 UIBezierPath 初始化方法
you could also just create an empty path, and
但是你也可以只建立一个空的路径
then you can start moving around.
然后你就可以开始在周围移动了
So, here I'm going to assume this screen is 160 points wide
所以，在这里我们假设这个屏幕是 160 * 250
by 250 wide, and I'm gonna draw, this triangle here.
然后我准备在这里绘制一个三角形
So I'm gonna move to 80 which is halfway across and
所以我准备移动 80 个点，大概在屏幕中间
50 which is a little bit down,
和 50 个点一点点下降
and then I'm going to add a line down to 140, 150.
然后我将要添加一条线向下到 140，150
Then I wanna another line over to 10, 150.
接下来我想再添加另一条线到 10，150
Then I'm going to close this path.
然后我将会关闭这个路径
Okay?
看明白了么？
So that's it, that's how you can make a triangle.
所以，这是这样，这就是如何绘制一个三角形
Now, I'm kind of lying to you a little bit, because as you
现在，我有点儿欺骗了你们一下，因为当你们
execute these, nothing is appearing on screen.
这么做的时候，屏幕上什么也不会出现
The screen will be blank.
屏幕将会一片空白
Okay, I was only showing them so you could understand what I
Okay，我只是向你们展示它们，这样你就可以理解
was doing there with the lines.
我在这儿通过这些线做了什么
So it'd be blank.
所以它将会一篇空白
To make it appear, you have to stroke or fill.
要让它出现，你必须描边或者填充
So, let's set the attributes we want.
所以，让我们设置我们需要的属性
So, I'm gonna set the color for filling to be green, and
所以，我将填充的颜色设置为绿色
the color for stroking to be red.
描边的颜色设置为红色
Okay, now notice that I set those with methods on UIColor,
Okay，现在注意我是通过 UIColor 的方法设置这些属性
not with methods on the BezierPath.
不是通过 BezierPath 的方法
Okay, that's a little interesting but
Okay，那是有一点有趣但是
that's the way that works.
它就是那样工作的
But linewidth, I do step by talking to the paths, so
但是线宽，我得通过和路径进行沟通来做
I sent a message to the BezierPath,
所以我发送一个消息到 BezierPath
set linewidth the three.
设置线条的宽度为 3
So once I set up all my attributes, now I can fill,
所以当我设置我所需要的全部属性后，现在我可以填充
for example by saying, path fill and
比方说，填充路径
see, I get the rectangle filled in green.
看，我得到了一个填充为绿色的三角形
Or, I can say stroke and it'll stroke the red line.
或者说，我可以给它描边，它将会变成红边
Okay?
明白了么?
Pretty straightforward?
很简单吧？
Most of learning to draw is all about
大多数的学习绘制全都关于
understanding UIBezierPath and all the methods on it.
理解 UIBezierPath 和它全部的方法
Question back there?
这里有什么问题么？
>> if I have two shapes onscreen,
-（学生提问）如果我在屏幕上有两个图形
>> how would I set the colors be different for each one?
- 我怎么样给每个图形不同的颜色呢？
If you have two what?
如果你有两个什么？
>> If you have two different shapes onscreen?
- 如果你在屏幕上有两个图形
Oh, yes. So, the question,
哦，是的，这就是问题
if I have two shapes onscreen,
如果我在屏幕上有两个图形
how would I set the colors be different for each one?
我怎么样给每个图形不同的颜色呢？
I would set the colors, stroke or fill one.
我可以给一个设置颜色，描边或者填充
Set the colors on something else, stroke or
给另一个设置其他的颜色，描边或者
fill the other.
填充
Okay?
明白了么？
Question.
问题
>> If the path isn't closed, what does fill do?
- 如果路径不是闭合的，那怎么去填充呢
So the question is,
这就是问题
if the path is not closed, what does fill do?
如果 path 不是闭合的，填充的结果是什么？
Well, it depends on, I think the winding rule, and,
我想它取决于绕圈规则，以及
other things about how it draws.
其他如何绘制的一些东西
But, it will try to fill it in.
但是，它会努力去填充
Okay. I mean a path could
我的意思是 path 可以
cross back over itself.
回头和自己相交
Right? And so filling it
对吗？对这种情况进行填充
might be hard to understand.
可能很难理解
And so there are rules for that.
所以有相应的一些规则去处理
I'll talk about that just briefly in just a second, but
我简要地介绍一下
it will fill.
它会去填充的
But there are other things, if you don't close a path then
但是对于别的操作，如果你没有闭合 path
you can't do things like hit detection, right?
那么你没法做类似碰撞检测等操作，对吗？
Detecting whether a point is inside it
检测一个点是不是在它里面
because it's not closed, so there's no inside.
因为没有闭合，所以它没有内部
So you can, UIBezierPath also has kind of
所以你能，UIBezierPath 有各种
pre-canned cool shapes like roundedRect, okay,
预制的漂亮图形，比如 roundedRect
which is a rectangle that the corners are rounded off of, or
它是四个角被磨圆了的矩形
obviously ovals and circles, it has ways of doing that.
或者干脆是椭圆跟圆形，它有处理这些的方法
You can also clip to any arbitrary path.
你也可以剪切任意的 path
So clipping,
所以对于剪切
hopefully everyone knows what that means.
希望每个人都明白它的意义
That means, if I set it up, if I have a path, and I say clip.
它意味着如果我设置好了，我有一个 path，我要剪切
If I say, addClip, then all drawing I do after that
如果我说，addClip，那么在这之后所有的绘图操作
will only show up if it's inside that path, okay?
只会影响到 path 里面的部分，okay？
So, for example,
举个例子
if you were drawing playing card on screen,
如果你正在屏幕上绘制纸牌
playing cards have little rounded rects, so you might
纸牌有小小的圆角效果，所以你可以
draw your playing card in a big rectangle, and then clip
把纸牌画在一个大的矩形里面，然后剪切到
to a rounded rect, so that the corners get cut off, okay.
一个圆角矩阵里，这样四角就修圆了
That's a cheap simple way to get a rounded rect playing card.
这是一个获得圆角纸牌便宜而又简单的方法
You can also do hit detection as I mentioned, the hit
你也可以做我提到的碰撞检测，碰撞检测
detection and the filling depends on the winding rules,
和填充取决于绕圈规则
and there's this usesEvenOddFillRule, property,
这里有 usesEvenOddFillRule 属性
which is only yes or no to say which winding rule it uses.
bool 类型，指定了它使用的绕圈规则
And so people who don't know what that means,
所以不了解它含义的同学们
don't worry about it.
不用担心
In fact, don't worry about hit detection or
实际上，不用担心碰撞检测
any of this stuff,
或者类似的 API
cuz you're not going to have to do this for your homework.
因为你们的课外作业里不用做这些
But I just want you to know that BezierPath has a lot of
不过我希望你们能了解 BezierPath 拥有许多
other stuff besides just line to, line to,
其他东西，不仅仅是画线条
fill and stroke.
填充和描边
Okay, it has other stuff.
Okay，它有别的东西
And when you want to look at UIBezierPath,
当你想要查看 UIBezierPath
check out its documentation and
可以打开相关文档
kind of experience it in its full glory.
经历它的各种荣耀
Okay, let's talk a little bit more about colors because I
Okay，我们再聊一聊颜色
used a color there, that green color.
因为我在那里用了一种绿色
UIColor is just an object.
UIColor 是一个对象
It's really powerful.
它非常强大
Colors not only can be
它不仅仅是
standard colors like UIColor.greenColor, but
类似 UIColor.greenColor 的标准颜色
you can create a color from RGB, red, green, blue, or
你也可以用 RGB，红绿蓝，或者
HSB, that's hue, saturation, and brightness.
HSB，色调，饱和度，亮度来创建颜色
You can even set your color to be a pattern, so that when you
你甚至可以把你的颜色设置为一个模式，这样当你
draw with that color, it actually draws some image.
用那种颜色绘制时，它实际上画出的是图像
Okay?
So that's kinda cool.
这个相当酷
Views have a backgroundColor, which you can set on them.
你可以给 view 设置 backgroundColor
Also colors can be transparent.
颜色也可以是透明的
Okay?
They can be see-through, partially see-through.
他们可以是透明的，半透明的
This is called alpha.
这叫做 alpha（透明度）
So alpha is a value between zero and one.
alpha 是一个介于 0 和 1 之间的值
Zero means fully transparent, so
0 代表完全透明
you can see completely through it, and
你的视线可以完全穿过去
it won't even show up on the screen.
它甚至不会出现在屏幕上
To one, which is fully opaque.
1 代表完全不透明
It obscures anything behind it.
它遮挡了背后的所有东西
Anything drawn with this color.
用这种颜色绘制的任何东西
And you can create a transparent color from
并且你可以通过 colorWithAlphaComponent() 方法来
another color with this color with alpha component.
生成某种颜色的透明色
This would create kind of half transparent yellow.
这里创建了一种半透明的黄色
Color to draw with, and you can draw in your view with
用于绘制，你可以用这些透明颜色
these transparent colors, okay?
来绘制你的 view，okay？
Using these BezierPaths.
使用 BezierPaths
However, if you draw in your view with transparency,
然而，如果你要用透明度来绘制
you must tell the system that you are going to do that.
你必须告诉系统你要这么做
And you do that by setting this property on
实现这个，你需要设置
your UIView called opaque to false.
UIView 的 opaque 属性为 false
And why is this required?
为什么需要这么做？
Well, because drawing with transparency is expensive.
因为带透明度的绘制是非常昂贵的
Because the views behind you
因为你后面的 view
are gonna start showing through.
会被展示出来
Okay? So the system has to
Okay？所以系统必须
blend basically the different views that are overlapping.
把重叠的 view 混合起来绘制
That's expensive in terms of graphics power.
这在图像处理能力上非常昂贵
And so it doesn't wanna do that if it doesn't have to.
所以如无必要别这么干
If it can just draw the bit.
假设它在绘制某个点
If you don't set this to false and
如果你没有把这个设置为 false
you try drawing transparently, it's not gonna work.
并且你还要画成透明的，那不会成功的
Okay?
Cuz it's not gonna blend with the things behind.
因为它不会把后面的东西混合进来
You can make your entire view transparent.
你可以把整个 view 设置成透明的
Okay?
It has its own property alpha,
它有自己的 alpha 属性
which you can set to anywhere between zero and one.
你可以设置 0 到 1 之间的任意值
It'll make your view,
它会使你的 view
everything you draw in the view will be
你在 view 上绘制的所有东西
however much transparent you want it to be.
带上你想要的任意透明度
Okay?
What happens when views overlap and have transparency?
当带有透明度的 view 互相重叠时会发生什么？
They're blended as I said,
它们会像我说的那样混合
remember that the subview's order matters.
记住 subview 的顺序有影响
Okay? The thing that is first in
Okay？subview array 里的第一个
the subviews array is in the back.
出现在最后面
And everything down the array is in front.
array 里剩下的 view 按照顺序出现在前面
So, when the transparency happens,
所以，当透明度产生时
that's the order it's gonna happen in.
这就是将要发生的顺序
You can completely hide a view by sending it hidden equal to
你可以完全隐藏一个 view，只要把它的 hidden 设置为
true, and this is surprisingly common to just hide a view,
true，这种隐藏一个 view 的做法非常普遍
and maybe it appears when a certain condition is true on
当某个条件成立它可以出现在屏幕上
screen, or whatever you can set up this view in
或者在你的 StoryBoard 里创建这个 view
your StoryBoard and then set it to hidden, to true.
然后把 hidden 设置为 true
And so it comes up, it's not there.
所以它出来的时候，你看不到
And then in code you say hidden equals false, boom,
然后你在代码中设置 hidden 为 false，轰隆
it appears, okay?
出现了，okay？
So that's a way to, completely hide the view.
所以这是个彻底隐藏 view 的方法
A hidden view not only doesn't draw,
隐藏的 view 不仅不会被绘制
it doesn't receive any touch events either.
也不会接受任何触控事件
But it's still in the view hierarchy.
不过它依旧存在于 view 的层级关系中
It's kinda there waiting.
有点像在那等待
Okay?
All right, drawing text.
好的，绘制文本
So, usually you draw text on screen with a UILabel.
通常你们用 UILabel 在屏幕上绘制文本
That's what you did with your display, et cetera.
这就是你用你的显示做的事，等等
But you might wanna draw in your drawRect and
不过你可能想要在 drawRect 上绘制
you do that with this class called NSAttributedString,
你用 NSAttributedString 来干这个
which I'm really not gonna cover.
这部分我不准备讲解
You wanna look at
你可以查看
its documentation if you wanna draw a text.
它的文档，如果你想要绘制文本
I'm not gonna do a demo of NSAttributedString, but
我不会给出 NSAttributedString 的演示，不过
I'm gonna give you some code for
我会给你们一些代码作为
your assignment next week, and I'm
下周的作业
gonna use NSAttributedString in the code I'm giving you,
我会在给你们的代码里使用 NSAttributedString
so you'll be able to see an example of how it's used.
所以你们能看到如何使用它的例子
But basically NSAttributedString is
但是基本上 NSAttributedString
a bunch of characters and
就是一串字符和
some attributes on those characters.
设置在这些字符上的一些 attributes（属性）
Now attributed String has a couple of interesting things
现在 AttributedString 有一些有趣的
about it.
特点
It's easy to use.
它易于使用
You can just create it, pass it a String, and
你可以创建它，传入一个 String
then say drawAtPoint, and that will draw the String with
然后调用 drawAtPoint，然后 String 就画出来了
its point, its upper left corner at that point.
参数指定了它的左上角位置
And you can even find out how big it's gonna be by asking it
你可以查看它将要占用的大小
the size of this attribute String.
调用 size 就行
So it's pretty easy to use in that way.
这么做非常容易
Mutability is not done with var and
var 跟 let 无法为 NSAttributedString
let for NSAttributedString.
带来可变性
There's a different class
有另一种 class
called NSMutableAttributedString.
叫做 NSMutableAttributedString
Okay? And why would you
Okay？为什么你们
want a MutableAttributedString?
想要一个 MutableAttributedString 呢？
Well because these Strings,
因为这些 String
what makes an AttributedString attributed,
AttributedString 之所以是 AttributedString
is you can put attributes on the characters in this String.
是因为你可以在 String 的字符上面设置 attributes
And so a MutableAttributedString,
所以对于 MutableAttributedString
you can set the attributes.
你可以设置 attributes
You can get the String out as an NSString,
你可以把里面的文本导出为 NSString
using the string property on NSAttributedString but
用 NSAttributedString 的 string 属性
NSAttributedString itself is not a String.
但是 NSAttributedString 本身不是 String
It's not like a subclass of NSString or anything.
它不是 NSString 的子类或者别的
It's its own thing.
它属于它自己
So you set
所以你们
these attributes with functions like setAttributes.
用 setAttributes 等函数设置 attributes
It takes a Dictionary of attributes.
它使用一个 Dictionary 类型的 attributes
I'll talk to you about what the keys and
我稍后介绍它的各种 keys
values are in a second.
跟 values
And then a range.
还有 range（范围）
That's an NSRange right there by the way, not a Swift Range.
注意是 NSRange，不是 Swift Range
And the indexing into these Strings is
这些 Strings 的索引
the old style NSString version.
是 NSString 版的古老风格
It's not the string.index stuff we
它不是 string.index 这样
talked about last time.
上次我们讲过了
It's literally which Unicode character are you
字面上的意思是在哪个你关注的
talking about setting an attribute at?
的 Unicode 文字上面设置一个 attribute？
Okay?
So, this Dictionary has a bunch of attributes.
所以这个 Dictionary 有一串 attributes
The attributes can be things like,
attributes 可以是类似
set the foreground color of this text.
设置文本的前景色
Okay?
Set the stroke width.
可以是设置描边的宽度
Okay? Because remember,
Okay？记住
text is just paths.
文本就是一些 paths
You can stroke them and set the width or the font,
你可以对它们描边，而且可以指定宽度或者字体
is a really important one to be able to say.
这是值得一提的重要能力
Set this text to have this particular font, okay?
（attributes 可以是）对文本使用特定字体，okay？
And so you just set a Dictionary that has
这样你只要设置一个
the key NSFontAttribute and the value would be a UIFont.
key 为 NSFontAttribute，value 为 UIFont 的一个 Dictionary
Okay?
Now let's talk about UIFonts, briefly.
现在我们简要讨论一下 UIFonts
Fonts in iOS 7 and later, including iOS 8,
Fonts 从 iOS 7 开始，包括 iOS 8
are very important to get right, okay?
正确使用非常重要，okay？
Look at these screenshots.
请看这些截图
Look how important the fonts are.
看下这些字体有多么重要
Okay? They're critical,
Okay？它们是
to making the UI look good.
创建漂亮 UI 的关键
Okay?
So, you've got to get the right fonts in your app.
所以你需要让你的 app 拥有一个合适的字体
And where do you get the right fonts?
那么怎么能够使字体合适呢？
Well, the number one place to get a font,
使这个字体合适的，
the right place 99% of the time, is this class function
百分之九十九都能使你的字体好看的，是这个在 UIFont 这个类
in UIFont called preferredFontForTextStyle, okay?
里面的一个类函数，叫 preferredFontForTextStyle
The text style is something like headline, or
字体样式是类似标题，或者
a body, okay?
正文这些东西
The body would be like the main content that your user is
正文就是你展现给用户看的主要的
looking at.
内容
Headline might be like a title at the top.
标题一般就是顶部的这个标题
Footnote might be a small little thing mentioned at
注脚是在底部的一行小小的字，
the bottom, okay?
好吧？
And there's a whole bunch more of these text styles.
这里还有很多很多这种字体样式
And so, you're gonna ask
那么你可能会问，
the assistant give me the preferred font for that style.
这个字体助手给我了一个对应这种样式的推荐的字体
The font includes a size. Okay?
这个字体包含了字体大小
UIFont include the size, as well as the face.
UIFont 包括了其大小以及它的样子
And users can go into their settings on their phone and
用户可能会去设置里面改变了一些字体相关的设置，
change and say I can't see it anymore.
比如老花眼了看不清楚那些字
Kinda like me.
像我一样
And they make their fonts bigger. Okay?
那么他们设置大一点的字体
And so this would
那这个推荐字体将会
automatically get that new size.
自动地获取到新的字体大小
Okay? So that's why you
所以你
always wanna use preferred font any
用这个推荐的字体总是好的，
time you're displaying any user content, okay?
在任何时候都是，尤其是你要展示给用户看的时候
Now, it is possible to create fonts where you say,
你当然可以自己创建一个字体，
give me Arial 15 narrow or what.
比如说，给我一个 15 号大小的窄体 Arial 字体
It is possible, but you really shouldn't be doing that.
你可以这么做，但是你不该这么做
You should be using this preferred font for style.
你还是乖乖地用推荐的字体
There's also a system font.
这里也有系统默认字体
This is something that appears on buttons and
比如出现在按钮上的，或者
in things like Segmented Controls, things like that.
出现在 Segmented Control （UI控件的一种）上的
You never wanna use only the system fonts for user content.
你永远不会只想用系统设置的是吧？
User content you wanna use the preferred fonts. Okay?
你更希望用推荐的字体来显示你的内容给用户看
So yeah, other ways to get fonts, ignore them.
啊这里是些其他获得字体的方法，忽略它们
I'm not gonna talk about it, okay?
在这里我不会讲它
All right, how about drawing images?
好的，那么怎么显示图像呢？
How do you do that?
你会怎么做？
Well there is a UILabel for
我们有个专门负责图像的 "UILabel"
images, it's called UIImageView.
叫 UIImageView
And you can use that to put an image on screen, but
你可以用这个类把图像显示到屏幕上，但是呢，
you might wanna draw an image, in your drawRect as well.
你可能希望把这个图像丢到你的 drawRect 里面
And usually you create an image by name, from that
一般来说你会以名字来创建这个图像，
Images.xcassets thing that we moved out of the way real
从 Images.xcassets 里面拿出来，
quick right at the beginning of our very first demo.
一会第一个演示一开始就会给大家瞅瞅
And if you click on that, it's pretty self-explanatory.
如果你点击它，故名思议
You can drag images.
你可以拖动图像
You can have different images of different resolutions for
你可以根据不同的分辨率，不同的设备，
different devices.
设置不同尺寸的图像
It's really pretty powerful.
总之就是很强大
That's usually how you create an image.
这就是一般创建图像的步骤
By name and dragging into the Images.xcassets.
通过图像的名字，拖进 Images.xcassets 里面
You can create it in other ways from the file system,
你也可以用其他方法从系统文件中创建出来，
which we haven't talked about, or even with drawing, but
我们还没讲到这些，包括怎么画图像，
we're not gonna talk about that either.
我们也不会讲这些
Once you have the UIImage, you can draw it by just sending it
当你有了这个 UIImage，你可以发送一个消息去显示它，
the message, drawAtPoint.
这个函数是 drawAtPoint
And it will draw in its normal size with that point as
然后这个函数就会把正常尺寸的的图像在左上角的那个点上
it's upper left.
显示出来
You can also say drawInRect, and
你也可以用 drawInRect 这个函数，
it'll scale to fit that rect, either bigger or smaller, or
它会缩放图像让其适应这个长方形区域，可以放大或者缩小，或者
you can draw a pattern in rect it'll tile it repeatedly to
你可以在这个长方形区域里面画一个图案，它会不断地重复平铺，
fill the rect. Okay?
铺满整个长方形区域
So really easy to draw images inside your drawRect.
在你的 drawRect 里面显示图像真的是很简单
And the last thing I wanna talk about is,
那么关于这个我想补充的是，
what happens when your bounds changes in your UIView?
如果你的 UIView 的边框变了咋办？
Like the, the user rotates the phone.
比如说用户旋转了他的手机
Now your bounds are wide and
现在你的边框变得胖矮胖矮的，
not very tall, instead of tall and not so wide.
不是以前那样高瘦高瘦的
You might think,
你也许会想，
oh my drawRect's gonna get called, and I'm gonna redraw.
噢我需要再调用一次 drawRect，然后就会重新适应
But no, that does not happen.
但这是不可能的
Instead, the bits that were on screen get stretched.
相反，在屏幕中的图像会被拉扁
Okay? So, usually that's not what you want.
所以一般来说得不到你想要的效果
You can and
你将会
result in a very grainy, kind of bit stretching of your UI.
使其变成马赛克那样，有点强行拉大了图像
But that is the default,
但这是默认设置
is the bit stretching because it's higher performance.
默认就会将图像拉伸，因为其有更好的性能
Now, you control though, you can control what happens to
其实呢，当边界改变了，你可以控制
your view when the bounds change,
你的 view 的变化，
with this property in view called contentMode.
用 view 中的一个叫 contentMode 的属性就能做到
And here are some of the contentModes you can set.
这里有些你可以修改的 contentMode，
There's left, right, top, bottom, et cetera.
这里有上下左右等等
All these ones basically don't change the bits.
这里的这些修改基本上不会像刚才那样的改变
They don't re-draw, but
它们不会重新显示图片，但是
they just move your entire view to the left edge,
它们只是让你的 view 整体移动到新的边界的左边，右边，
right edge, top, or bottom of the new bounds.
上边或者下边
These are kinda strange ones.
这是些奇怪的属性，
You probably don't need that very often.
一般来说你应该不会用到
Then there's the scaling of the bits.
这里是些缩放，
So here's the default, ScaleToFill.
默认的是 ScaleToFill
'Kay, we'll scale the bits to fill the new bounds, but
我们会缩放图像去填满新的边界，但是
you can also fill or fit the bounds and
你仍可以填满或者适应边界，
keep it aspect ratio.
而且保存图像原来的长宽比例
So that won't stretch your bits.
这些就不会再拉伸你的图像了
It'll still scale them, but
它们可以缩放，但是
it'll scale them with your aspect ratio maintained, or
是以原来的长宽比例来缩放的，或者
you can have the wonderest Redraw, 'kay?
你也可以用你最想用的 redraw
This is the one you wanna set that says,
你心想：我设成这样，
when my bounds change, call my drawRect again.
当我的边界发生了变化，再次调用我的 drawRect 函数
Okay? With the new bounds.
有了新的边界
So you're gonna want that quite often.
你将会常常需要用到它
I'll show you that in the demo today.
我会在今天的展示中做给你们看
All right, so let's get right to this demo.
好的，那我们开始展示吧
Today, it's gonna be a little tight to do this in 20 minutes
今天这个展示的时间有点紧，因为还剩20分钟了，
but, cuz we're gonna cover a lot of stuff but
因为我们今天讲了好多东西，但是
I think we can do it.
我觉得我们应该够时间的
We're going to start by creating a new project.
我们开始创建一个新的项目
So I'm just going to file a new project,
点击 file -> new -> project，
this is brand new.
全新的一个项目
Okay? We're going away from
我们将暂时把我们之前的
the Calculator here.
计算器放一边
And as always we're gonna be
就像之前一样我们将
using the single view application thing right here.
用这里的 Single View Application
I'm gonna call this project Happiness,
我将这个项目命名为 Happiness，
because we're gonna draw a face, a smiley face.
因为我们将会展示一个笑脸，
Okay? And it's gonna be
它将能够
able to smile or frown, depending on how happy it is.
微笑或者皱眉，这取决于它有多开心
Okay? So that's why we're gonna call this Happiness.
所以我们命名为 Happiness
I'm gonna put it in the same place I put my Calculator,
我把它放在我的 Calculator 项目的位置，
which is my home directory developer there.
也就是我的 home 目录下的 developer 里面
Here it is.
就是这里
As before I'm gonna move this AppDelegate out of the way.
像之前一样我将会把这个 AppDelegate 放开一边
I'm gonna move, actually let's take a look at image.xcassets.
我将会移...等等我们先看看这个 image.xcassets
So here's the appicon slots.
这里是 Appicon（应用图标）的空槽
You can see that for any given image,
你可以看到，对于不同的图像，
like the appicon, there's lots of different resolutions,
像这个 Appicon，它有很多不同的分辨率
depending on the devices that you can provide. Okay?
取决于你提供的设备
You don't have to provide all the different resolutions,
你不必提供所有的分辨率，
it will interpolate but you can do it.
它会自己添加，但你也可以都提供
So you just drag an image into here, and now you can get it
那么先把这个图像拖进来，然后你就能通过图片名来指定了，
by name with that UIImage named function.
用 UIImage 那个函数
So we'll get that out of there.
我们还是先把它放出去
We don't want the launch screen either.
我们也不想要 LaunchScreen
So here we are.
就先这样
I'm gonna show you something fun here too.
我将给你们展示一些有趣的东西
Here is my StoryBoard.
这是我的 StoryBoard
I'm gonna show you how to add a new View Controller to
我将给你们展示一下怎么把一个新的 View Controller 添加到
your StoryBoard.
你的 StoryBoard 中
And in fact, I'm gonna delete this one.
事实上我将删除这一个
So, you see this one right here I've selected?
看到我选择的这个了吗？
I'm just deleting it.
然后我删除它
It's gone. I'm gonna delete its
删掉了同时我也将删除它的
code as well.
代码
I'm gonna go here, and just delete, move it to the trash.
我点击这里，然后删除，将其移除到垃圾箱
Now I have a StoryBoard with nothing in it, and
现在我有一个啥都没有的空 StoryBoard，
I've no View Controllers.
里面也没有 View Controllers
Okay?
So, how do I add a View Controller?
我怎么添加一个 View Controller？
You go over here to your Object Pallet.
你点这个 Object Pallet（Xcode 最右下角）
The very first thing is a View Controller.
这里的第一个就是 View Controller
And you just drag it out, and boom.
然后你拖出来，哗的一下，
You've got one.
你得到了一个 View Controller
Now, the class.
现在，它的类，
What class is this going to be though?
它的类是什么呢？
This is gonna be Generic UIViewController, so
它是一个普通的的 UIViewController
it's pretty useless.
所以这并没什么用
Okay? You can't add any outlets, or
你不能用它来添加 outlet （IBOutlet）
have any actions because it's not a subclass of UIViewController,
也不能添加任何 action，因为它不是 UIViewController 的子类，
so you can't put any of that implementation in.
所以你不能在里面放任何实现功能的代码
So, we're gonna create a new subclass of UIViewController.
因此我们需要创建一个 UIViewController 的子类
So let me show you how to do that.
让我来给你们展示一下
You say New > File.
新建一个文件， New -> File
And last time we went to New > File,
上回我们这么做，
we said Swift file to make the CalculatorBrain.
是新建 Swift 文件来创建 CalculatorBrain
But now we're gonna go over here to Cocoa Touch Class,
但是现在我们选择这个 Cocoa Touch Class，
which we do anytime we wanna create a subclass of an iOS class.
每当我们想要新建 iOS 的子类的时候，我们都会选择它
And here I'm creating a subclass of UIViewController.
这里我要创建一个 UIViewController 的子类，
I need this.
那么我就需要它
So I'm gonna click on that.
点击一下
Here's where I pick what I want it to be a subclass of.
在这里我选择我想要继承的类
You can see there's a lot of things in here.
你可以看到这里有很多东西
I'm gonna say I want a View Controller.
我想要一个 View Controller
It wants to call it ViewController by default.
它默认名字就是 ViewController
We don't even like that for
我们甚至在我们的 Calculator 中
the Calculator, let alone this.
都不这样叫，更别说这个了
So I'm gonna call this my HappinessViewController.
我想叫它 HappinessViewController
Okay? So it creates that.
这样就创建好了
Put it in the same place all my other Swift files are.
把它放在我其他的 Swift 文件那里
Here it is.
搞定了
HappinessViewController.
Again, I'm gonna get rid of this code.Okay?
再一次，我将把这些代码删掉
Just to make things a little clearer.
让它看起来更简洁
So here's my HappinessViewController.
这个就是我的 HappinessViewController
It's just like the View Controller you had,
就像是之前的 View Controller 一样，
that was called ViewController in your Calculator.
我们在 Calculator 叫 ViewController
It was called HappinessViewController.
这里呢我们叫它 HappinessViewController
But this guy right here,
但是这里的这个家伙，
is still playing old View Controller.
还是以前的 View Controller
How do I know that?
我怎么能知道呢？
Well, it's this magic right here.
神奇的东西在这里，
You see this Identity Inspector?
你看到这个 Identity Inspector 了吗？
Okay. You can see the class of
你可以看到被选择的东西的类，
this selected thing here, in this UIView Controller.
在这里是 UIViewController
And I don't want it to be UIViewController.
我不想让其是 UIViewController
I want it to be HappinessViewController.
我想让它是 HappinessViewController
So, very important to understand that in
明白这里很重要，在 StoryBoard 里，
StoryBoards, everything is linked up to
所有东西都用名字和你的代码
your code by name.
相连接
Only by the name.
只用名字
That is the only thing that links what's in
这个是唯一连接
your StoryBoard with your code.
你代码和 StoryBoard 的东西
The names of outlets, the names of methods,
outlet 的名字，method 的名字，
the action methods.
action 的名字
The name of your UIViewControllers.
你的 UIViewController 的名字，
The name of your UIViews.
你的 UIView 的名字
Okay? It's all by name.
好吧？所有的都是和名字有关
So you have to go to the Identity Inspector here and
所以你需要到 Identity Inspector 这里，然后
make sure that name matches up.
保证你的名字对得上号
So now, you can see
现在你可以看到，
this says that it's a HappinessViewController.
这里说它是一个 HappinessViewController
So that's making me happy. Okay.
这让我很快乐
Now, we want to put our custom view in here, okay?
现在我们想把我们自定义的 View 放进去，
So how do I add a custom view to my UI?
那我怎么把这个自定义的 View 放进去呢？
And the answer is, I go into the Object Pallet.
答案就是，我又一次选择 Object Pallet
It's all the way at the bottom,
一直滚下去，
near the bottom somewhere.
知道就快到底部的时候
Where is that thing?
在哪里呢？
There it is.
在这里
You can drag out a generic view.
你可以拖出一个普通的 View
So this is just a UIView.
这其实是一个 UIView
Now when I drag it out,
现在当我拖出来
I'm gonna put it right here with the dashed blue lines.
我将把它放在这些虚蓝线这里
'Kay, because we know that that's a good thing to do.
因为我们知道这么做总是好的
And I want to set up the AutoLayout so
我想要设置 AutoLayout，因此
that this view always fully fills my scene here.
这个 View 将填满我的整个画面
Okay? Now I could Control drag to
现在，我可以按住 Control 拖动到边缘，
the edges like I did before, but since this is already
就像我之前做的那样，但是现在这已经
perfectly where I want it, and I use the blue lines, I
很完美了，所以我用这些蓝线
can go down here and use Reset to Suggested Constraints. 'Kay?
我可以在下面用这个 Reset to Suggested Constraints
Now, I'm only showing you dribs and drabs of AutoLayout.
现在我只是一点点地向你们展示 AutoLayout
I wasn't gonna talk all about Auto Layout today, but
我不会在今天讲 AutoLayout 的，但是
we need to move on to this.
在这里我们需要这么做
But I will be having the lecture on AutoLayout,
我会专门有节课讲 AutoLayout，
probably week after next.
也许是下下周
In the meantime I'm just gonna show you little bits of it and
同时我会展示一点点，
you can explore.
让你们摸索一下
I'm never gonna ask you to do a ton of it in your homework.
我不会让你们在作业中做很多这个，
So this one I'm gonna Reset to Suggested Constraints, and
所以对于这个我将选 Reset to Suggested Constraints，
it added those Constraints.
然后它就添加了这些 Constraints（约束）
And I could go over here.
我可以点击这里
Let me make some more space here.
让我在这里腾出多一点空间
I could go look at them over here.
我可以在这里浏览到它们
You've all determined that.
你已经确定了这些
Another place you can see the Constraints of a view is
另一个能看到 View 的这些 Constraints 的地方是
here in the Size Inspector.
在这个 Size Inspector 这里
If you look towards the bottom of the Size Inspector-
如果你看 Size Inspector 的最底部，
Look, here's all the Constraints, see?
看，这里就是全部的 Constraints，看到么
Trailing, leading, top, bottom.
It added all these because these are the Suggested
这里添加的全部都是刚刚添加的
constraints based on the dash blue lines that I used. Okay?
Suggested Constraints，基于刚刚我用的那些蓝色虚线
So, oftentimes if you put something in place perfectly
一般来说你把东西都放到刚刚好的位置，
with the blue lines,
放到有蓝线的位置，
you can use Reset to Suggested Constraints.
你就可以用 Reset to Suggested Constraints
We coulda done that with our display in our Calculator.
我们也可以在在我们的 Calculator 中的显示结果的那个地方使用
We couldn't do it with the buttons.
但是我们不能用在按钮上
Cuz it just wasn't lined up enough with other things, but
因为它并没有和其他的物体排列起来，但是
we could have done it with the display.
我们可以用于显示结果的那里
All right? So now we have this.
好的，现在我们有了这个
Now, this UIView, let's look at its Identity Inspector.
这个 UIView，我们看看它的 Identity Inspector
It's just a generic UIView.
它是个普通的 UIView
That's no good.
这并不好
We need a custom UIView sub-class.
我们需要一个自定义的 UIView 子类
So let's go do that.
我们来实现这个
File > New File.
选择 File > New File
Same thing,
一样的，
I'm gonna create a subclass of a Cocoa Touch Class.
我将创建 Cocoa Touch Class 的子类
This one's not gonna be a View Controller,
这次不是一个 View Controller，
it's gonna be a UIView.
而是一个 UIView
Okay? I'm gonna call it FaceView,
好的，我将叫它 FaceView，
cuz that's what it's gonna do.
因为它要做的就是，
It's gonna draw a face, okay?
显示出一张脸
Put it in the same place, put everything.
将它放在同一个地方，放所有文件的地方
Here's our, my FaceView right here.
这里是我们的 FaceView
We'll get back to that in a second.
我们一会再回来这里
In our StoryBoard,
在我们的 StoryBoard 中
we wanna make sure that we inspect our FaceView.
我们想确保我们能观察我们的 FaceView
Okay? And change its class to FaceView.
然后把它的类改成 FaceView
By the way, it can kinda get tricky sometimes,
顺带说一句，选择到一个你想要的东西，
picking the right thing.
有时候会比较困难
Like, sometimes you're picking the UIViewController,
比如说有时候你想选择 UIViewController，
sometimes you're picking the view.
但有时你会不小心选到 View
One kinda cool trick, Control + Shift.
有个酷炫的小技巧，就是按 Control + Shift
If you hold Control + Shift and click, then it
如果你按住 Control + Shift 然后点击，它会
lets you pick which thing you want, that's under the mouse.
在这个鼠标位置后面，有许多东西，它会让你选择其中一个
A very important little trick, Control + Shift.
所以，这个是一个很重要的小技巧，Control + Shift
So here I could pick the View Controller.
这里我可以选择 View Controller
Now I'm seeing the Identity Inspector of
现在我看到，Identity Inspector
the View Controller.
是我选择的那个 View Controller
Or I could go here and pick,
同样，我可以在这里选择
this is the view property in my View Controller.
这是我的 View Controller 中的 view 属性
The top level view.
最顶层的 view
This is my FaceView that I'm trying to create.
这是我想要创建的 FaceView
So I select this here, then I'm gonna go to
所以我选择这个，然后我来到
the Identity Inspector again, up here.
上面的 Identity Inspector
I'm gonna change this to be a FaceView. Okay?
并将其改成 FaceView
So now this thing is a FaceView, and so
那么现在这个 view 就是 FaceView 了
when it's time for this thing to draw,
当有需要绘制的时候
it's gonna call the drawRect of the FaceView class.
这将会调用 FaceView 类里的 drawRect 方法
So let's go take a look at the FaceView class.
所以现在我们来看看这个 FaceView
Here it is.
这里就是 FaceView 的代码
And here is drawRect.
这里是 drawRect 方法
Now, it's commented out by default.
现在，它默认是被注释的
Why is it commented out by default?
为什么默认被注释掉呢？
Well because having a drawRect costs system resources.
因为调用 drawRect 会消耗系统资源
It thinks it has to draw this thing.
系统认为需要重绘这个东西
So you only wanna have a drawRect if you actually draw,
所以当你确实需要手动绘制的时候，你才需要实现 drawRect 方法
in your drawRect.
Don't have it just sitting there uncommented out,
当你并不需要手动绘制的时候
if you're not actually using it.
别让 drawRect 方法取消注释但不做任何操作
All right, so, how am I gonna draw this face?
好的，我怎么画这个脸出来呢？
Let's start by drawing the outline of the head.
我们从画头的轮廓开始吧
Just a round circle. Okay?
一个圆圈
Cuz that's pretty simple to draw.
因为这很简单
And how am I gonna do that?
我该怎么做？
Let's start by creating a BezierPath.
我们开始创建一个 UIBezierPath 吧
I'll call it facePath which is, BezierPath.
我叫这个为 facePath，是一个 UIBezierPath 对象
And let's look at
让我们看看
all the different kinds of BezierPaths we can make.
我们能用 UIBezierPath 绘制的所有东西吧
Ovals.
椭圆形
We could use this one, ovalInRect, okay?
我们可以用 ovalInRect 这个方法
That's a pretty good one.
这是个不错的选择
I'm actually gonna use this one,
事实上，我要用这个
arcCenter cuz I wanna show you a really bad error message
arcCenter，因为我想向你们展示一些你将会在 Swift 中遇到的错误信息
you're gonna get in Swift that I want you to avoid.
我希望你们能够避免这些地方
So I'm gonna use this one which lets you create an arc,
所以我需要这个，让你创建一个弧
and I'm just gonna have my arc go all the way around.
然后我想让这个弧绕成一个圆
Okay? From zero all the way around.
从 0 度到 360 度
So, it wants to know the center.
它需要知道中心点在哪里
So I'm gonna have to have my faces center somehow.
我假设这里有一个 faceCenter 是这个圆的中心点
We'll define that in a second.
我们稍后会定义它
It also wants to know the radius, so
同样，这个方法需要知道半径是多少
I have to have my faces radius in a second.
所以我同样假设这里有一个 faceRadius 是这个圆的半径
We'll do that.
同样我们稍后定义它
It wants to know the start angle, to draw this arc.
另外，它还需要知道画这个弧度的起始角度
Okay? So
这里
I'm gonna start at angle zero.
我将从 0 度开始
The angle's in radians.
半径是用弧度来计算的
So I wanna go around to 2pi.
所以我希望它能从 0 度画到 2pi
Going, I'm gonna draw an arc from zero,
继续，我将从 0 度开始画这个弧
all the way around to 2pi radians.
绕一圈直到 2pi 的弧度
Hopefully everyone knows what radians are. Okay?
希望所有人都知道弧度是什么
So zero to 2pi that's good, and then clockwise or
所以，0 到 2pi，没问题了吧？，顺时针还是
counter clockwise,
逆时针
I don't care cuz I'm going all the way around.
我不在乎是顺还是逆，因为我画的是一个整圆
So I'll just say clockwise true.
所以我选择顺时针，clockwise: true
Now, when I do this, well first let's do
现在，当我这么做，我们先定义
our faceCenter and faceRadius here.
我们的 faceCenter 和 faceRadius 吧
So I'm gonna make actually computed properties for those.
事实上我将会让这俩变成 computed properties
So the faceCenter is a CGPoint.
faceCenter 是一个 CGPoint
And really, it would be cool, yeah, I could do get and set.
作为一个 computed properties，我可以编写 get 和 set 方法
It's gonna be Get Only. Okay?
但在这里我只需要 get
I'm not gonna allow me to set my faceCenter,
我不允许用户来设置 faceCenter 的值
I'm almost going to calculate it.
get 方法大部分工作就是计算
I could make it settable, actually too, but
事实上我也可以让 faceCenter 能够被赋值，但
I'm gonna make it so it's calculated only.
这里，我只让它能够计算
When you do calculated only,
当你只用做计算时
you actually don't need this part.
你就不需要编写 get  这部分
This get.
这里的 get
You can take that out.
你可以把它删去
And if it's returned Only.
而且，如果它只是返回一个数值
So I'll say return.
我会写 return
Now I, you might be saying oh I'm gonna return center,
现在你也许会写 return center
let's put the face in the center.
把我们的 FaveView 放在 center 上吧
Did everyone understand why this is very bad?
大家都明白这里为什么错了吗？
All right, cuz center is not in my coordinate system.
因为这个 center 并不在我的坐标系中
It's in my superview's coordinate system.
它在我的 superview 的坐标系中
Luckily, I can convert a point from my superview's coordinate
不过幸运地，我可以把这个点从 superview 的坐标系转换到
system using this nice method, convertPoint(fromView:).
我的坐标系中，用一个很好用的方法叫 convertPoint(fromView:)
So I'm gonna convert center from my superview. Okay?
所以我从 superview 转换 center
That's gonna put my face right in the center,
这将会让我的笑脸放在正中心
cuz I've converted that center from my superview's coordinate
因为我从 superview 的坐标系转换过来
system to mine. Okay?
成为我的坐标系的 center
So that's faceCenter.
那么这个就是 faceCenter 了
Let's also do faceRadius.
接着来定义 faceRadius
So for the faceRadius,
那么对于这个 faceRadius
I'm gonna have it be as big as it can be. Okay?
我将希望它尽可能的大
So faceRadius is gonna be a CGFloat to all of
faceRadius 会是 CGFloat 类型的
our drawing stuff is Float, and I'm gonna return as big as
所有的绘画元素都是 Float 类型的，在它不会被截断的情况下
it can be without getting cut off.
我会让它尽可能大
So it's gonna be the minimum of my width or height.
所以，让它成为宽和高中较小的那一个
So I'm gonna say, min of my bounds.
这里我输入 min(bounds
Sorry.
抱歉
bounds.size.width, or my bounds.size.height.
min(bounds.size.width, bounds.size.height)
Whichever is less than that.
哪个短用哪个
Min is just a nice little function in Swift.
Swift 中的 min 是一个不错的小函数
And I'm gonna divide by two because this is a radius,
这里把它除以 2，因为这是半径
not diameter of my face.
不是直径
This is the radius.
这就是 faceRadius
So now I have my center facing radius, but
现在我有了半径和中心
I still have an error here.
但是这里还是有个错误
Look at this error.
来看看这个错误
Even though I did my center, I did my radius.
即使我算好了中心位置，算好了半径
I still have an error.
这里还是有错误
What is the problem?
到底是什么问题？
Oh, "Extra argument 'radius' in call".
噢，"Extra argument 'radius' in call"
Huh.
That's weird.
这很奇怪
I didn't see any extra argument.
我没看到额外的参数
What the heck is that about?
到底出什么错了？
Okay.
You could waste a half an hour looking for this, okay?
你可能会花半个小时找错误
I was thinking, oh,
你可能会想
radius, there's nothing wrong with the radius.
radius，radius 这里也没什么问题啊
It's right.
是的
The problem for this has nothing to do with the radius.
radius 跟这个问题一点关系都没有
The problem is this.
问题在这，2*M_PI
Okay?
明白了吗？
So this is an error you get from switching occasionally,
这个错误你们可能会偶尔遇到
I'm sure they'll fix all these errors, but occasionally,
我确定 Apple 会修复好这些错误
you get this very misleading error, and this is one.
但是偶尔还是会获得这些误导你的错误，这就是一个
The problem is that this-
问题在于
What type is this?
它的类型是什么？
It's a Double.
它是一个 Double
Yeah.
是的
And what type do we draw with?
但是我们绘画用什么类型的？
CGFloat.
CGFloat
So this problem is just that I need to cast this to
所以把它转型成 CGfloat，这个问题就可以
a CGFloat.
解决了
Okay?
明白了吗？
That's gonna make this error go away.
这个错误就会消失了
It had nothing to do with radius whatsoever there.
跟 radius 一点关系都没有
Okay?
So, best warning, watch out for that.
这就是我给你们的提醒，以后要注意点
All right, so I have my nice facePath here.
我已经得到了 facePath
Maybe I wanna set my facePath's lineWidth.
在这里设置一下 facePath 的 lineWidth（线宽）
Something like three, something like that.
设置成 3 吧
In fact, maybe I even want lineWidth to
我想把 lineWidth 变成 FaceView 中
be something that's configurable in my FaceView.
可以设置的一个属性
So it's a CGFloat.
类型是 CGFloat
And we'll set it to default of three.
我们把它的默认设置为 3
One thing that's interesting and
一个很有趣的事是
then we'll set this down here to lineWidth.
我先把这里设置成 lineWidth
One thing that's interesting about this is any time
一个有趣的事情是，无论何时 lineWidth 被改变了
someone changes my lineWidth, I need to redraw myself.
我都需要把这个 view 重新绘制一遍
All right?
明白了吗？
So how can I make that happen?
我怎么做才能实现呢？
Well, I can use Property Observer.
我可以使用 Property Observer
Okay?
Anytime someone sets this,
无论什么时候，有人改变了它
I'm gonna call setNeedsDisplay on myself.
我就会在向自身调用 setNeedsDisplay
Okay?
明白了吗？
Bam.
I'm in it redrawn by the system.
系统就会帮你重新绘制视图
Okay? So anytime you have
如果在你的 view 中有一个
a property in your, in a view that changes how you would be
property 在改变的时候需要被重新绘制
drawn, just put a little Property Observer into
只要在 Property Observer 里调用
the setNeedsDisplay after it.
setNeedsDisplay 就可以了
And it'll get you automatically redrawn.
它就会帮你重新绘制
Maybe I'll have another property here,
在这里我还想添加一个
which is the color I wanna be.
颜色的 property
UIColor, we'll set the default here to be
类型是 UIColor，默认设置成
blueColor for example.
蓝色
But I want the exact same thing here.
但我也想跟这里一样
Okay?
Someone sets it.
有人改变了它
I want it redrawn.
视图就会被重新绘制
And so let's go ahead and set our color.
现在设置一下颜色
Now I'm gonna do both my set, I could do setFill and
我既可以做 setFill 又可以做 setStroke
setStroke colors, but I'm just gonna do set,
我两者都想做，但这里，只要 set 就可以了
which sets both my fill and my stroke.
这样填充和笔画的颜色都会被设置
I'm not gonna be filling so it doesn't matter, but set to
因为这里不会被填充，所以调用 set 也没问题
both, and then how do I draw this BezierPath right here?
然后呢？我怎么绘制 BezierPath？
I just say, facePath.stroke.
facePath.stroke 就可以了
And that's gonna draw, okay?
这样就可以绘制了
So let's go take a look at this.
我们运行一下程序
Okay.
So, it comes up, it's blank.
运行起来了，它是空的
And not only is it blank, it's got some error down here.
不仅仅是空白的，这里还有一些错误信息
What does it say? It says,
它说
failed to instantiate the default View Controller.
failed to instantiate the default View Controller（初始化默认 View Controller 失败）
Okay? Well that means that in my
这表明
StoryBoard, there is no scene that's specified,
在 StoryBoard 中，没有指定
as the scene to start in.
开始场景
Okay? It has no starting scene.
没有开始场景
The starting scene always has a little arrow pointing to it.
开始场景总是有一个指向它的小箭头
Right here,
在这里
you've probably seen in in your Calculator right?
你们可能在 Calculator 中已经见过了
A little arrow that says this is the place to come in
当你运行程序时
when you start this app.
一个代表程序入口点的小箭头
You can set that arrow with the Inspector the regular
你可以在选中的 View Controller 的
Attributes Inspector by selecting your
Attributes Inspector 里
View Controller that you wanna be the one that comes in.
设置它为入口场景
And click. This little button here is
点击这里的小按钮
Initial View Controller.
Is Initial View Controller
You see that arrow appear?
看到剪头出现了吗？
You can also pick this arrow up and
你也可以把这个剪头选中
move it to another View Controller.
把它移动到另一个 View Controller 里
Okay?
So now we have a thing, oh all right.
好了
So we've got our face.
脸已经出现了
Now, one thing I don't like about this face is it goes all
现在我对这个脸不满意的地方就是
the way to the edges.
它太靠近边缘了
I want it to actually be 90% of the edges.
我想让它占据整个长度的 90%
Okay? Another thing I
另一件
don't like is this.
我不满意的事情是
Ugh, okay?
额
So my face is gonna be distorted every time I rotate.
每一次我旋转屏幕，脸都会被破坏
Why is that?
这是怎么回事儿？
That's this stretching thing I was telling you about.
这就是我之前告诉你们的拉伸的情况
We want our drawRect to be called again when we
我们希望每一个获得新的边界时（就像旋转屏幕）
have a new bounds like that.
drawRect 都会被再一次调用
So let's fix both of those things.
现在我们一起把它们处理好
We can fix that content mode redraw by selecting our view,
修改 Mode （重绘模式）的方法是：选中 view
going to the inspector up here,
去到 Inspector
the Attributes Inspector, and
Attributes Inspector
the very first one is the mode.
第一个就是 Mode
And you can see the default was scale to fill.
默认的是 Scale To Fill (拉伸以填充)
We want Redraw.
我们想要 Redraw (重绘)
Okay? So I'm gonna pick Redraw.
所以我选择 Redraw
So that'll fix that.
这样就修改好了
And as far as the 90%, I'm going to fix that in here,
至于 90%，我在这里修改
by having the, my face radius be times 90%.
把 faceRadius 再乘以 90%
But really, I'd like this to be settable too.
但是我也想让它成为一个可以被设置的
So I'm gonna have var scale, CGFloat.
添加一个变量 scale，类型是 CGFloat
Okay. And we'll start this out at
默认设置为
90%.
So I want that, and
我想让它
this one also, if I change, I want it to change.
在更改以后也重绘视图
Okay?
So now let's go try that.
运行一下程序
See what happens.
看看发生了什么
Okay? We got our 90%.
90% 已经实现了
That's good.
还不错
And when I rotate, it doesn't stretch it.
当我旋转屏幕时，也没有拉伸
Okay? And it's using the minimum of
它使用了宽度和高度中
the width or height.
较小的那个
Okay?
So that's good.
还不错
That's going good.
越来越好了哈
Now we wanna draw the eyes and the mouth, and
现在开始绘制眼睛和嘴巴
cuz time is running out here,
时间已经不多了
I'm actually gonna type those in super fast.
我将会用超快的速度输入
I posted for those of you who are trying to keep along here,
我会贴给你们这些源代码，所以
which is probably impossible.
就不要尝试手动输入了
To do that though, I need some constants.
为了实现这些，我需要一些常量
And this how we do constants in Swift.
在 Swift 中我们这样定义常量
We create structs.
创建 struct
Okay? And then use class, or
使用 class 或者
in this case, static lets.
在这里使用 static let 修饰
Okay? So this is gonna be
所以这个常量就是
a constant called Scaling.FaceRadiustoEyeRadius.
Scaling.FaceRadiustoEyeRadius
Okay. And
then I'm going to have a function here, that I'm
这里有个函数叫做 bezierPathForEye
gonna type in really, really fast, called bezierPathForEye.
同样我这里用了 Code Snippet
And it's just gonna return a BezierPath that draws an eye.
它会返回一个绘制一只眼睛的 BezierPath 对象
Either the left eye or the right eye.
左眼或者右眼
This says which one.
参数用来确定是哪一只眼睛
Okay? So it returns a BezierPath.
它返回了一个 BezierPath
Okay?
Then I'm gonna have another one, which is BezierSmile.
这里还会有一个函数，BezierSmile
We're gonna type that in real fast.
再一次使用 Code Snippet
Okay?
没问题吧？
So here is BeizerPath for smile.
这就是笑容的 BeizerPath
And what this is gonna do,
这个函数会
it's gonna take a fractionOfMaximumSmile.
把 fractionOfMaximumSmile 作为参数
So one is full smile.
1 是最开心的笑容
Minus one is full frown.
-1 是最难过的
And everywhere in between.
其余的值都在 1 和 -1 之间
'Kay? So that's what this does.
这就是它做的事情
And it returns a BeizerPath.
返回一个 BeizerPath
So now here in my drawRect,
在 drawRect 函数中
I can say bezierPathForEye, left eye.
调用 bezierPathForEye，left 作为参数
I got the BezierPath.
我获得了 BezierPath
I'm just gonna immediately send it stroke.
我立即用它调用 stroke
Okay?
And then BezierPath for the right eye.
接着是右眼的 BezierPath
I'm gonna send it stroke.
给它发送 stroke 消息
So I'm just gonna stroke the left eye and the right eye.
现在绘制了左眼和右眼
Okay?
Then I'm gonna do the smiliness.
接着处理笑容
So, I'm going to let smiliness equal some value.
我在这里写 let smiliness =
Let's start it at 0.75.
从 0.75 开始吧
We're pretty, pretty happy to start.
这是一个很开心很开心的数值了
And then I'm going to create a bez,
接着，我用上面的这些给笑容
this BezierPath using this thing up here for
创建一个 BezierPath
a smile, which is bezierPathForSmile.
用这个函数 bezierPathForSmile
And we're gonna pass it the smiliness.
把 smiliness 传进去
And then I'm just going to stroke this smile path.
然后绘制这个笑容的线条
Okay?
And I hoped to have a little more time so
我很希望能有时间
I could have gone through this code, but
跟大家一起分析代码
it's a pretty straightforward code, really.
但是这些代码都很易懂
Here we're just using addCurveToPoint in
这里，我们在 BezierPath 里
our BezierPath.
调用 addCurveToPoint
To draw a curve, which is the curve of the mouth.
接着，我们绘制嘴部的曲线
And then here,
接着，这儿
we're just using BezierPath arcCenter again.
我们又调用了一次 BezierPath(arcCenter: ...)
Okay?
To create the circle.
为了绘制圆
The eyes are just circles, okay?
眼睛都是圆的
That's really all those two methods do.
这就是这两个方法做的事情
There's nothing really special about them.
没什么特别的
And what do I have error here, which is, oops.
这里有个错误
Dot.
点
Okay?
That's not it either.
不是点
SmilePath oh, equals, not that.
SmilePath 等于，
Equals.
等号
There we go.
这就对了
Okay?
Yes?
有问题吗？
So let's run this.
运行一下程序
Hopefully, we'll have a smiley face.
希望我们能有一张笑脸
There it is.
来了
He looks pretty happy.
他看起来很快乐
We can rotate him.
我们可以旋转屏幕
He's very happy.
他真的很快乐
Okay, let's make him a little sad.
来，我们让他难过一点
How about minus 0.5?
-0.5 怎么样？
Minus 0.5.
-0.5
Pretty, pretty sad.
非常非常难过
Aw.
Okay?
明白了吗？
Okay.
好的
So now we have this nice FaceView.
FaceView 已经完成了
What we're gonna do in our next lecture, is we're going
下一次课要讲的是
to add a gesture so we can make him happy or sad.
给这个程序添加手势，我们就可以让他一会儿开心一会儿难过
Happy or sad.
开心或者难过
Okay?
We're also gonna put a gesture in there, a pinch gesture so
我们也会加入 Pinch Gesture (缩放手势)
we can make them bigger or smaller.
我们就能把他变大或者变小
Okay?
Then we're going to actually add a whole another MVC and
接着我们会添加另一个完整的 MVC
make a much more powerful application that just uses
使用 FaceView 制作一个
the FaceView.
更强大的应用
The HappinessViewController as a view in another MVC.
把 HappinessViewController 用作另一个 MVC 的 view
Okay?
So now we're going to do multiple MVCs.
我们接下来就会处理多个 MVC 了
So that's what we're gonna be doing on Monday.
这就是下周一要完成的事情了